CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE
BY NEW LINE HOME VIDEO
DEREK.
FUCKING PERVERT, DAN.
JESUS, DANNY,
WHAT THE FUCK ARE YOU THINKING?
THERE'S A BLACK GUY OUTSIDE.
HE'S BREAKING INTO YOUR CAR.
HOW LONG'S HE BEEN THERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
NOT RIGHT NOW, HONEY. HOW MANY?
DANNY, HOW MANY?
ONE, I THINK.
IS HE STRAPPED? HUH?
DOES HE HAVE A FUCKING GUN?
MAN, I DON'T FUCKING KNOW.
WAIT A SECOND. WHAT
THE FUCK IS GOING ON?
STAY RIGHT HERE
JESUS! AND BE QUIET.
WAIT A SECOND, DEREK. WAIT.
DEREK!
SHH, SHH, SHH, SHH.
Stay right here.
AAH!
Murray: I DON'T HAVE A
PERSONAL PROBLEM WITH HIM, OK?
Sweeney: DON'T INSULT
MY INTELLIGENCE, MURRAY.
YOU HATE THIS CHILD,
AND I THINK I KNOW WHY.
Woman: DR. SWEENEY'S OFFICE.
I WENT OUT WITH HIS
MOTHER A FEW TIMES.
THAT WAS 3 YEARS
AGO. IT WAS NOTHING.
NOTHING. REALLY? HMM.
THAT PAPER... BOB,
IT'S A TRAVESTY,
ARGUING FOR HITLER
AS A CIVIL RIGHTS HERO.
YOU'VE GOT TO DRAW THE LINE.
YOU KNOW, MURRAY, YOU
ACTUALLY DID THIS TO YOURSELF.
YOU TOLD THEM THAT
THEY COULD DO A REPORT
ON ANY BOOK THAT RELATED TO
THE STRUGGLE FOR CIVIL RIGHTS,
IN PLAIN ENGLISH.
I AM NOT DISPUTING THE FACT
THAT THE CHILD IS CONFUSED,
AND HE HARBORS SOME SICK IDEAS,
BUT I AM NOT READY
TO GIVE UP ON HIM YET.
HIS BROTHER PROBABLY
PUT HIM UP TO IT.
I CAN GUARANTEE YOU 100%
HIS BROTHER DID NOT
PUT HIM UP TO THIS.
I FIND THAT HARD TO
BELIEVE. WHATEVER.
LOOK, I KNOW HE WAS A GOOD KID,
AND IT'S A SHAME WHAT
HE'S BEEN THROUGH,
BUT THAT IS DANGEROUS.
DANGEROUS IN WHAT WAY?
THAT GOES TOO FAR.
THIS RACIST PROPAGANDA,
THIS MEIN KAMPF PSYCHOBABBL-
HE LEARNED THIS
NONSENSE, MURRAY,
AND HE CAN UNLEARN IT, TOO.
I WILL NOT GIVE UP
ON THIS CHILD YET.
I KNEW IT WAS YOU.
Sweeney: DANNY, GET IN HERE.
I SAID GET IN HERE!
GET IN HERE!
5, 4, 3, 2...
SHUT THE DOOR!
WHAT'S IT GONNA BE, DANNY?
WHAT'S WHAT GONNA BE?
THIS PETTY CRAP YOU'RE PULLING.
I DON'T KNOW.
HAVE A SEAT.
AHEM.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
FINE.
THINGS AT HOME OK?
YEAH.
DEREK GOT OUT THIS
MORNING, DID HE NOT?
YEAH, HE DID.
HE WAS ONE OF MY STUDENTS.
YOU KNEW THAT, RIGHT?
HONORS ENGLISH.
HE WAS A BRILLIANT STUDENT...
LIKE YOU...
BUT HE HUNG OUT WITH
SIMPLE-MINDED FOOLS,
ALSO LIKE YOU.
LOOK, SWEENEY,
DID YOU BRING ME IN HERE
TO TALK ABOUT DEREK?
BECAUSE WHAT HAPPENED TO
HIM HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH ME.
EVERYTHING YOU DO RIGHT NOW
HAS SOMETHING TO DO WITH DEREK.
LOOK, I FOLLOWED DIRECTIONS.
I WROTE AN "A" PAPER.
MEIN KAMPF?
I SHOULD EXPEL YOU.
GO AHEAD.
WHAT, YOU DON'T THINK
I COULD HANDLE IT?
NO. I THINK THE
STREET WOULD KILL YOU.
YOUR RHETORIC AND
YOUR PROPAGANDA
AREN'T GOING TO
SAVE YOU OUT THERE.
SO HERE'S THE DRILL.
I'M YOUR HISTORY
TEACHER FROM NOW ON.
WE WILL DISCUSS CURRENT EVENTS.
WE WILL CALL THIS CLASS...
AMERICAN HISTORY X.
WE MEET ONCE A DAY.
ALL RIGHT. YOUR FIRST ASSIGNMENT
IS TO PREPARE FOR ME A
NEW PAPER DUE TOMORROW.
OH, COME ON, SWEENEY.
IT TOOK ME A WEEK
TO READ MEIN KAMPF.
THAT ISN'T FAIR.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU
WANT ME TO DO IT ON?
YOUR BROTHER.
OH, GOD, MAN. PLEASE
TELL ME YOU'RE JOKING.
NO, NO, NO. I'M NOT KIDDING.
I WANT YOU TO ANALYZE AND
INTERPRET ALL THE EVENTS
SURROUNDING DEREK'S
INCARCERATION...
HOW THESE EVENTS HELPED
SHAPE YOUR PRESENT PERSPECTIVE
CONCERNING LIFE IN
CONTEMPORARY AMERICA.
THE IMPACT ON YOUR LIFE,
YOUR FAMILY'S.
WHATEVER YOU WANT TO SAY, DANNY.
I'LL BE THE ONLY ONE READING IT.
BUT IF IT'S NOT ON MY
DESK TOMORROW MORNING,
YOU ARE A GHOST AT
VENICE BEACH HIGH.
YOU CLEAR?
YEAH, I'M CLEAR.
TELLING TEACHER
I'M FUCKIN' CHEATIN'!
IS THAT WHAT'S HAPPENING?
I NEVER CHEATED IN MY LIFE.
BEAT HIS MO'FUCKIN' ASS.
BUT I DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING!
WHY YOU TRIPPIN' ON ME?
NOW WHY YOU ALL
KICKING IT LIKE THAT?
WHAT'S UP, MAN?
WHAT YOU SCARED FOR?
I AIN'T GONNA DO NOTHING.
WHAT'S UP?
WANT SOME, TOO, BITCH?!
PUNK, WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
YOU WANT TO DIE?
PUNK-ASS WHITE BOY.
YOU LUCKY I GOTTA GO TO CLASS.
HE AIN'T GONNA DO NOTHING.
HE DON'T WANNA SEE
ME AND THE HEATER.
LUCKY THE BELL RUNG.
I WOULD HAVE CLOCKED
THAT WHITE BOY.
PUNK-ASS MOTHERFUCKER.
SHOULD SMOKE THAT FOOL.
YOU GOTTA FUCKING
STAND UP FOR YOURSELF.
Cop: WE GOT A WHOLE
FILE ON SKINHEADS HERE.
Second cop: SKINHEADS ALL
PART OF THE SAME GANG?
VENICE BEACH GANG.
Third cop: ACTUALLY, HE'S
DONE A STRETCH AT Y.A.
THIS GUY C.C.,
IS THAT HIM?
YEAH, THAT'S HIM RIGHT THERE.
THIS MORNING WE HAVE A GUEST
COMING IN, AND THERE HE IS.
GOOD MORNING.
MORNING, SIR.
GOOD TO SEE YOU, PAL.
GOOD MORNING.
GENTLEMEN, THIS HERE
IS DR. BOB SWEENEY.
HE'S PRINCIPAL OVER
AT VENICE BEACH HIGH,
AND FOR SOME TIME NOW, HE'S
BEEN DOING OUTREACH WORK
WITH GANGS BOTH IN
AND OUT OF THE CAN.
3 YEARS AGO, A LOCAL
KID NAMED DEREK VINYARD
WAS SENT UP FOR
MURDERING A COUPLE OF CRIPS
WHO WERE TRYING TO JACK HIS CAR.
BOB TAUGHT VINYARD
BACK IN HIGH SCHOOL,
AND HE'S FOLLOWED THE
CASE KIND OF CLOSELY.
HE WAS A SKINHEAD, RIGHT?
HE WAS MORE LIKE THE SKINHEAD...
THE PROTéGé OF
CAMERON ALEXANDER.
WHO?
HERE YOU GO. HAVE A LOOK-SEE.
CAMERON ALEXANDER, WELL...
HE'S A VENICE BEACH LANDMARK.
HE'S PROBABLY THE BIGGEST
DISTRIBUTOR AND WRITER
OF WHITE POWER LITERATURE
AND VIDEOS IN L.A. COUNTY.
HE PROMOTES WHITE POWER
BANDS, HE WRITES REVIEWS,
AND IN HIS SPARE TIME,
THIS GUY EVEN
WRITES HATE COLUMNS.
DOES HE HAVE A RECORD?
HE'S PRETTY CLEAN.
BEEN TRYING TO PIN SOMETHING
TO HIM, BUT IT DOESN'T WORK.
TRUST ME. HE'S BEHIND ALL OF IT.
HE RUNS EVERYTHING
OUT OF HIS HOUSE
DOWN BY THE BEACH.
THERE WERE NO WHITE
GANGS IN VENICE BEACH
BEFORE CAMERON ALEXANDER
AND DEREK VINYARD HOOKED UP.
ALEXANDER FOUND IN
DEREK HIS SHINING PRINCE.
ESSENTIALLY, HE USED
DEREK TO RECRUIT A SLEW
OF INSECURE, FRUSTRATED,
AND IMPRESSIONABLE KIDS.
THIS KID VINYARD, WELL,
HE'S GOT A LOT OF BAGGAGE,
AS YOU'LL SEE ON THIS TAPE
WE'VE GOTTEN COURTESY OF NBC.
EARLIER TODAY, L.A. COUNTY
FIREFIGHTER DENNIS VINYARD
WAS SHOT AND KILLED
BATTLING A BLAZE
AT A SUSPECTED COMPTON DRUG DEN.
WE'RE AT THE VINYARD
HOME RIGHT NOW,
AND LIEUTENANT VINYARD'S
OLDEST SON DEREK
HAS AGREED TO TALK
WITH US FOR A MOMENT.
DEREK, IF YOU COULD
COME DOWN HERE PLEASE
FOR JUST A SECOND.
LOOK, I KNOW THIS IS TOUGH,
BUT HOW DO YOU FEEL RIGHT NOW?
HOW DO YOU THINK I FEEL?
I THINK IT'S TYPICAL.
TYPICAL HOW?
WELL, THIS COUNTRY'S
BECOMING A HAVEN FOR CRIMINALS,
SO WHAT DO YOU EXPECT?
DECENT HARD-WORKING
AMERICANS LIKE MY DAD
ARE GETTING RUBBED
OUT BY SOCIAL PARASITES.
PARASITES?
BLACKS, BROWNS,
YELLOW, WHATEVER.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU'RE SAYING THAT
YOU THINK MAYBE
YOUR FATHER'S MURDER
WAS RACE-RELATED?
YEAH, IT'S RACE-RELATED.
EVERY PROBLEM IN THIS
COUNTRY IS RACE-RELATED.
NOT JUST CRIME. IT'S, LIKE,
IMMIGRATION, AIDS, WELFARE...
THOSE ARE PROBLEMS
OF THE BLACK COMMUNITY,
THE HISPANIC COMMUNITY,
THE ASIAN COMMUNITY.
THEY'RE NOT WHITE PROBLEMS.
AREN'T THOSE REALLY ISSUES
THAT DEAL MORE WITH POVERTY?
NO. YOU KNOW, NO.
THEY'RE NOT PRODUCTS
OF THEIR ENVIRONMENTS.
THAT'S CRAP.
MINORITIES DON'T GIVE 2
SHITS ABOUT THIS COUNTRY.
THEY COME HERE TO
EXPLOIT IT, NOT TO EMBRACE IT.
WHAT DOES THIS HAVE TO DO...
MILLIONS OF WHITE EUROPEANS
CAME HERE AND FLOURISHED,
YOU KNOW, WITHIN A GENERATION,
SO WHAT THE FUCK IS THE
MATTER WITH THESE PEOPLE?
THEY HAVE TO GO AROUND
SHOOTING AT FIREMEN?
WHAT DOES THIS HAVE TO DO
WITH THE MURDER OF YOUR FATHER?
BECAUSE MY FATHER WAS
MURDERED DOING HIS JOB!
PUTTING OUT A FIRE IN A
FUCKING NIGGER NEIGHBORHOOD
HE SHOULDN'T EVEN
HAVE GIVEN A SHIT ABOUT.
HE GOT SHOT BY A
FUCKING DRUG DEALER
WHO PROBABLY STILL
COLLECTS A WELFARE CHECK.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
DEREK VINYARD WAS
QUIETLY RELEASED FROM CHINO
EARLY THIS MORNING
AFTER SERVING 3
AND SOME ODD YEARS.
I THINK THIS IS SOMETHING
WE GOTTA KEEP AN EYE ON.
IF SOMETHING HAPPENS TO HIM,
THINGS COULD GET VERY
UGLY DOWN BY THE BEACH.
JUST KEEP IT LOW.
Danny: VENICE BEACH DIDN'T
ALWAYS LOOK LIKE THIS.
IT USED TO BE A
GREAT NEIGHBORHOOD.
THE BOARDWALK'S
ALWAYS BEEN A DUMP,
BUT WHEN MY DAD
MOVED US OUT HERE,
VENICE WAS A NICE,
QUIET PLACE TO GROW UP.
OVER THE YEARS, THOUGH,
IT'S JUST GONE TO HELL.
THE GANGS ARE LIKE A PLAGUE.
THEY MOVED WEST FROM INGLEWOOD
AND SOUTH CENTRAL,
AND BASICALLY TOOK OVER.
I AIN'T FOULIN' YOU!
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
I AIN'T GOT TIME FOR
ALL THIS BULLSHIT.
FUCK Y'ALL.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'M ALL RIGHT.
HEY, YO, IS THAT THAT FOOL
YOU WAS TELLING ME ABOUT?
YEAH, THAT'S THAT MOTHERFUCKER.
YEAH, MAN, THAT'S HIM.
BITCH ASS MOTHERFUCKER.
Danny: THAT'S WHY
DEREK STARTED THE D.O.C.
HE SAID WHITE KIDS SHOULDN'T
HAVE TO WALK AROUND SCARED
IN THEIR OWN NEIGHBORHOOD,
AND FOR A WHILE THERE,
WE REALLY MADE IT
LIKE IT WAS OURS AGAIN.
THROW THE BALL, THROW THE BALL!
COME ON, CURTIS!
QUIT CHUCKING IT
UP. PASS THE BALL.
"D" UP!
Cameron: COME ON,
LET'S GO, LET'S GO.
Derek: LOOK AT THIS
FUCKING JUNGLE BUNNY.
HE DOES A SPIN MOVE
EVERY TIME. EVERY TIME.
YOU AIN'T GETTIN'
SHIT, MOTHERFUCKER.
YOU AIN'T GETTIN' SHIT.
THIS ONE'S FOR YOU, BOY!
WHAT THE FUCK YOU...
WHO YOU CALLIN'
BOY, MOTHERFUCKER?
YOU'RE LUCKY, MOTHERFUCKER!
I'M THROUGH MONKEYING
AROUND WITH YOUR FUCKING ASS!
PALE, PASTY, PASTRAMI-EATING,
CRACKER MOTHERFUCKER.
100 BUCKS SAY I
MAKE YOU MY BITCH.
HEAR THAT?
HE'S TRYING TO MAKE ENDS MEET
FOR HIS CUT IN WELFARE.
YOU'RE FUCKING ON!
IT'S 8-6, SETH.
DANNY, WHEN I WANT
YOUR FUCKING OPINION,
I'LL ASK FOR IT. COME ON,
GUYS. I CAN'T COVER THIS.
HELP ME OUT HERE.
YOU GOT A BIG
FUCKING MOUTH, SETH.
I CAN TAKE THIS NIGLET DOWN.
SETH, YOU COULDN'T TAKE A SHIT.
WHAT THE FUCK ARE YOU THINKING?
I WILL BEAT HIM.
GIVE ME THE MONEY.
SHUT UP, SHUT UP.
YOU'RE GONNA FUCKING
EMBARRASS US. SHUT UP!
I'LL TAKE CARE OF THIS.
Man: YO, I AIN'T
GOT TIME FOR THIS.
Derek: HEY!
I GOT A BET.
I COME IN THIS GAME
RIGHT NOW. SAME SCORE,
BUT WE PLAY BLACK GUYS
AGAINST THE WHITE GUYS.
YEAH?
NAME YOUR PRICE, CRACKER.
NO MONEY, NO MONEY.
FOR THESE COURTS.
AND NOT JUST TODAY... FOR GOOD.
IF YOU WIN, WE WILL WALK AWAY,
BUT IF WE WIN, NO
BITCHING, NO FIGHTING.
RIGHT HERE IN
FRONT OF EVERYBODY,
YOU PACK UP YOUR SHIT
AND GET YOUR BLACK
ASSES OUT OF HERE.
FUCK THAT. TAKE THIS BET.
8 TO 6. OUR BALL.
LET'S GO.
YES! WHOO!
Derek: PICK HIM UP! PICK HIM UP!
SETH, GET BACK
AND PLAY SOME "D."
DEFENSE!
ALL RIGHT!
PASS THE FUCKING
BALL! I WAS WIDE OPEN!
Seth: BULLSHIT, MAN.
THAT'S FUCKIN' OFFENSE.
MAN, GET THE FUCK OUT
OF HERE. HE MOVED HIS FEET.
YOU WANT TO GO, I'M READY!
DON'T BE THROWING
FUCKING ELBOWS AT ME!
YOU WANT TO GO, ADOLF HITLER
WANNABE MOTHERFUCKER?
YOU OK?
YEAH. JUST GIVE ME SOME WATER.
YOU GOTTA CALL OFFENSE
ON THAT SHIT, DER.
NOT ON GAME POINT, DANNY.
FUCK THAT. YOU CAN'T
LET THOSE NIGGERS
GET AWAY WITH THAT SHIT.
HONEY, IT'S GAME POINT.
SHUT 'EM DOWN,
DEREK. KICK SOME ASS.
WATCH THIS.
YEAH!
BYE-BYE.
GET THE FUCK OFF MY COURT!
THIS IS MY HOUSE!
FUCK YOU, BITCH!
WHOO!
YEAH.
GET THE FUCK OUT OF HERE!
THIS IS MY COURT!
YES!
Danny: DEREK WOULDN'T
LET US VISIT HIM IN PRISON.
HE SAID IT WOULD MAKE
IT JUST TOO HARD FOR HIM,
AND THAT IF WE CAME, HE
WOULDN'T SEE US ANYHOW.
3 YEARS WITHOUT
HIM, JUST WONDERING.
Danny: AND THEN AT
7:00 THIS MORNING,
WE PICKED HIM UP
OUTSIDE THE GATE.
DER.
Danny: THE WHOLE RIDE
BACK, HE DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING.
I WANTED TO STAY
HOME, BUT HE SAID, "NO.
GO TO SCHOOL.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER."
OH, COME ON.
GIVE THE GUY A BREAK.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU TOO BIG TO GIVE
ME A HUG, TOUGH GUY?
NO, MAN. I JUST KNOW
YOU'RE GONNA NEED SOMEONE
TO LOOK AFTER YOU WHILE
YOU ADJUST TO ALL THIS SPACE.
YEAH, RIGHT.
THIS PLACE IS SMALLER
THAN THE OLD LIVING ROOM.
HOW YOU DOING? HOW'S SCHOOL?
IT'S GOOD. IT'S GOOD.
YOU GOTTA DO SOMETHING
ABOUT THAT HAIR, MAN.
THAT DO'S GOTTA GO.
I DON'T KNOW. THE
GIRLS LIKE IT, SO...
WELL, I DON'T.
YOU'RE KEEPING IT PRETTY CLOSE.
YOU TOOK IT ALL
THE WAY DOWN, HUH?
SHIT. LOOK. I FORGOT, MAN.
IT HURT LIKE SHIT WHILE
THEY WERE PUTTING IT ON.
WHEN'D YOU GET THAT?
I GOT IT ABOUT A MONTH AGO.
CAMERON MADE IT OFFICIAL.
CAMERON?
YEAH.
HE PUT THIS ON YOU?
MM-HMM. YEAH.
Davina: HELLO?
WHAT?
Davina: OH, HI. HE'S HERE.
DEREK, IT'S FOR YOU.
NOTHING.
I'M GONNA GRAB IT. IS
THERE A PHONE IN THE BACK?
I'LL GET IT IN THE BACK.
I GOT IT.
YEAH?
OH, HEY.
WHAT?
♪♪ MY EYES HAVE
SEEN THE GLORY ♪♪
♪♪ OF THE TRAMPLING
AT THE ZOO ♪♪
♪♪ WE'VE WASHED OURSELVES
IN NIGGER'S BLOOD ♪♪
♪♪ AND ALL THE MONGRELS, TOO ♪♪
♪♪ WE'RE TAKING DOWN
THE ZOG MACHINE ♪♪
♪♪ JEW BY JEW BY JEW ♪♪
♪♪ THE WHITE MAN MARCHES ON ♪♪
YOU THINK OUR FRIEND
WAS BEHIND THAT?
WELL, YOU KNOW
WHAT? I DON'T EVEN CARE,
'CAUSE I'M GONNA TAKE
CARE OF THAT TONIGHT.
MY SWEET KIDS. MY BABY BOY.
GOD, WHAT'S WITH THE
LOVE FEST, YOU GUYS?
NO, NO. HE'LL DO IT.
HE'LL DO IT. I'LL MAKE
SURE HE DOES IT.
Davina: I'LL GET IT.
I CAME TO SEE THE MAN.
ARE YOU SURE YOU CAN FIT
THROUGH THE FUCKING DOOR?
FUCK YOU!
SETH.
Seth: WHAT'S UP, DAN?
HOW YOU DOING? WHERE'S DEREK?
HE'S ON THE PHONE.
COME OUT, YOU FREE MOTHERFUCKER!
VINYARD, WHERE THE FUCK ARE YOU!
HANG ON.
GIVE ME A MINUTE.
Seth: VINYARD!
I'LL BE OUT IN A MINUTE.
I'LL BE CAREFUL.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO?
I'M NOT GONNA STAY IN MY
ROOM THE REST OF MY LIFE.
HOLD ON.
HEY, HEY.
WHAT THE FUCK IS
SETH DOING HERE?
DID YOU INVITE HIM OVER?
NO. HE ALWAYS COMES OVER HERE.
DANNY, GIVE ME A MINUTE.
JUST GIVE ME ONE MINUTE.
YEAH.
ARE YOU STILL HERE, GOODYEAR?
YOU CALLING ME A BLIMP,
YOU FUCKING DEMOCRAT?
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU WERE ACTUALLY
ABLE TO SEE YOUR FEET?
COME IN HERE, DANNY.
SETH.
HEY, MAN, ARE YOU GOING
TO CAM'S PARTY TONIGHT?
IS DAVINA'S ASS WATERTIGHT?
YOU'RE FUCKING SICK, MAN.
ALL RIGHT, RELAX. LET ME
ASK YOU A FEW QUESTIONS.
I'M NOT IN THE MOOD. I
GOT HOMEWORK TO DO.
TELL ME SOME OF THE SHIT
YOU'VE LEARNED, FUCKASS,
BEFORE I PISTOL-WHIP YOU.
OK. I BELIEVE IN
DEATH, DESTRUCTION,
CHAOS, FILTH, AND GREED.
CUT THE SHIT, DAN. COME ON.
TELL ME WHAT I WANT
TO HEAR, ASSHOLE.
YOU MEAN THAT SHIT
ABOUT YOUR MOTHER, MAN?
YOU WANT TO GET
FUCKING BEATEN, DANNY?
I'M NOT FUCKING
TALKING TO YOU, DAVINA.
WHY DON'T YOU SHUT UP?
LOOK, YOU GOTTA LET ME DO
THIS MY OWN WAY, ALL RIGHT?
I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
WHO DO YOU HATE, DANNY?
I HATE ANYONE THAT
ISN'T WHITE PROTESTANT.
WHY?
THEY'RE A BURDEN
TO THE ADVANCEMENT
OF THE WHITE RACE.
SOME OF THEM ARE ALL RIGHT.
NONE OF THEM ARE FUCKING
ALL RIGHT, DANNY, OK?
THEY'RE ALL A BUNCH OF
FUCKING FREELOADERS.
REMEMBER WHAT CAM SAID?
WE DON'T KNOW 'EM. WE
DON'T WANT TO KNOW 'EM.
THEY'RE THE FUCKING ENEMY.
NOW WHAT DON'T
YOU LIKE ABOUT THEM,
AND SAY IT WITH SOME
FUCKING CONVICTION.
I HATE THE FACT THAT IT'S COOL
TO BE BLACK THESE DAYS.
Seth: GOOD.
I HATE THIS HIP-HOP
FUCKING INFLUENCE
ON WHITE FUCKING SUBURBIA.
GOOD.
AND I HATE TABITHA SOREN
AND ALL HER ZIONIST
MTV FUCKING PIGS
TELLING US WE SHOULD GET ALONG.
SAVE THE RHETORICAL BULLSHIT,
HILLARY RODHAM CLINTON,
'CAUSE IT AIN'T GONNA
FUCKING HAPPEN.
THAT'S SOME OF THE
BEST SHIT I'VE EVER HEARD.
DANNY, NO.
I FEEL SORRY FOR YOU, DANNY.
I KNOW YOU DON'T BELIEVE
ANY OF THAT SHIT, RIGHT?
SHUT UP, DAVINA.
NO. YOU SHUT THE FUCK UP.
GET OUT OF THE HOUSE
NOW, YOU PIECE OF SHIT.
IS THAT ANY WAY
TO TALK TO A GUEST?
A FRIEND OF THE FAMILY?
DEREK HATES YOU,
AND YOU DON'T EVEN REALIZE IT.
HEY, HEY, HOW DO YOU
KNOW WHO I HATE, DAVINA?
FUCKIN' A. BACK FROM THE DEAD.
GOD BLESS JESUS CHRIST.
GOD, I THINK YOU
LOST WEIGHT, MAN.
I CAN GET MY ARMS ALMOST
ALL THE WAY AROUND YOU.
50 FUCKIN' POUNDS, MAN.
LOOK AT THIS HAIR. HOLY SHIT.
I TOLD HIM IT'S GOTTA GO.
GRAB YOUR JACKET. LET'S
GET THE FUCK OUT OF HERE.
ALL RIGHT. I WANT TO
TALK TO HIM. ONE SECOND.
HEY, LISTEN.
DID YOU PULL SOME KIND
OF SHIT IN SCHOOL TODAY?
NO. JUST THE USUAL.
I'M TELLING YOU, MAN.
THIS KID IS AWESOME AS HELL.
DID YOU TURN IN A PAPER
ON MEIN KAMPF?
YEAH.
SWEENEY PROBABLY SHIT HIS PANTS.
HE DID, MAN.
WAS THAT YOUR IDEA,
OR DID CAMERON
PUT YOU UP TO THAT?
DID HE TELL YOU TO DO THAT?
NO, MAN. I THOUGHT
IT WOULD BE COOL.
HOW'D YOU KNOW, THOUGH?
IT DOESN'T MATTER HOW I KNEW.
THIS KID IS SMART AS HELL.
WAS THAT SWEENEY ON THE PHONE?
YEAH. SWEENEY
CALLED AND TOLD ME.
GOD, I HATE THAT
FUCKING NIGGER, MAN.
HE'S GOTTA GET A FUCKING LIFE.
NO, NO, NO.
SWEENEY'S A GOOD
TEACHER, ALL RIGHT?
SWEENEY IS A NIGGER
ON A POWER TRIP.
THAT'S WHAT HE WAS
LIKE WHEN WE WERE THERE,
AND THAT'S HOW HE IS NOW.
SETH!
FUCK THAT NIGGER!
SETH, GO AWAY.
ARE YOU KIDDING?
NOPE. GO WAIT IN DANNY'S ROOM.
I WANT TO TALK TO MY
BROTHER. I'M GLAD TO SEE YOU.
I'VE BEEN HERE 15
FUCKING MINUTES.
HURRY UP. I'M STARVING.
COME HERE. SERIOUSLY, LOOK,
FORGET THIS YAHOO, ALL RIGHT?
HE KILLS BUGS FOR A LIVING.
YOU DON'T WANT TO BE LIKE THAT.
NO.
I'M SERIOUS. IT'S NOT FUNNY.
SWEENEY IS A GOOD TEACHER.
YOU CAN LEARN A LOT FROM HIM,
SO DON'T GO FUCK IT UP
WITH SMALL FRY SHIT LIKE THAT.
YOU GOT TO BE SMARTER THAN THAT.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND, MAN.
YOU GOT TO SEE THE BULLSHIT
PAPER HE'S MAKING ME WRITE.
I KNOW ALL ABOUT IT.
HE TOLD ME ALL ABOUT IT.
I DON'T CARE.
AND YOU'RE GOING TO DO IT.
YOU DO ANYTHING HE
TELLS YOU TO DO. I MEAN IT.
I DON'T WANT YOU GETTING
IN TROUBLE IN SCHOOL
TRYING TO IMPRESS ME
TAKING THIS SHIT
IN THERE, ALL RIGHT?
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M SAYING?
YEAH, I GUESS, BUT, I MEAN...
I THOUGHT YOU'D BE HAPPY.
WELL, I'M NOT.
SHH.
LISTEN TO THAT.
YEAH, I KNOW. IT'S BEEN
GETTING WORSE, MAN.
ALL RIGHT, LOOK,
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
I'LL TALK TO YOU ABOUT
THIS LATER, ALL RIGHT?
OK.
HEY, SHE'S COUGHING
HER LUNGS OUT,
AND YOU'RE BLOWING THIS
SHIT IN HER FACE ALL DAY.
PUT IT OUT.
I'M PUTTING IT OUT.
ALL RIGHT. COME ON.
HEY...
COME ON, I WANT TO TALK TO YOU.
Ally: MOMMY,
ARE YOU OK?
OH.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING? PUT THAT OUT.
I WAS JUST YELLING AT HIM
FOR BLOWING SMOKE IN YOUR FACE,
AND YOU'RE IN
HERE SUCKING ON IT.
NICE THING TO COME HOME TO, HUH?
YEAH.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
LOOK...
YOU GOT TO TAKE
IT EASY, ALL RIGHT?
YOU GOT TO GET SOME REST.
I WANT YOU TO TAKE
DANNY'S AND MY ROOM,
AND WE'LL HIT THE COUCH.
NO. I'VE BEEN ON
THE COUCH FOR AGES.
THE COUCH IS FINE.
NO, IT'S NOT FINE. IT'S NOT.
THIS IS TERRIBLE. WE
CAN'T LIVE LIKE THIS.
WE GOT TO GET OUT OF HERE.
Ally: CAN I GO WITH YOU?
YEAH. YEAH, WE ALL
GOT TO GET OUT OF HERE.
THAT'S THE POINT.
I COULD DROP OUT OF
SCHOOL AND GET A JOB.
NO, NO. ABSOLUTELY NOT.
YOU GOT TO FINISH. I'LL
WORK SOMETHING OUT.
DEREK, CAN WE PLEASE GO EAT?
I'M FUCKING STARVING
HERE. I MEAN...
I DON'T GIVE A SHIT. GO
WAIT IN THE LIVING ROOM.
I WANT HIM OUT OF MY HOUSE.
I KNOW. LOOK...
HE'S AN IDIOT.
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN AN IDIOT.
WHATEVER, DUDE.
HE CAN'T HELP IT.
I GOT TO DO THAT PAPER.
LOOK, I'M GOING TO CATCH UP
WITH YOU LATER TONIGHT AT...
HEY, HEY, NOT AT
CAMERON'S HOUSE.
I NEED YOU TO STAY
AWAY FROM THERE.
BUT WHY, MAN? I THOUGHT
WE WERE GOING TO HANG.
TRUST ME. I WILL
EXPLAIN IT TO YOU LATER.
I JUST NEED YOU TO STAY AWAY
FROM THE PARTY, ALL RIGHT?
WHATEVER.
HEY, I'M NOT KIDDING.
PROMISE ME YOU'RE
GOING TO STAY AWAY
FROM THAT PARTY TONIGHT, DANNY.
I'M NOT FUCKING 14
ANYMORE, ALL RIGHT?
WHATEVER.
GOD!
COME ON, LET'S GO.
WHERE ARE YOU PARKED?
OUT BACK.
YEAH, THAT'S THE WHOLE BUNCH.
Danny: IT DIDN'T TAKE LONG
FOR DEREK TO MAKE
A NAME FOR HIMSELF,
AND CAMERON KNEW
JUST HOW TO USE IT.
YOU SURE YOU DON'T
WANT TO STICK AROUND?
OH, YOU KNOW I'D LOVE TO,
BUT I GOT TO BE CAREFUL.
YEAH, I KNOW.
I'LL SEE YOU BACK
AT THE HOUSE, THEN?
RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
GOOD LUCK.
Danny: HE SENT
DEREK TO THE KIDS...
TO THE FRUSTRATED ONES...
THE ONES WHO WERE SICK OF
GETTING THEIR ASSES KICKED
BY BLACK AND MEXICAN GANGS.
"DON'T JUST BE SOME PUNK.
BE PART OF SOMETHING."
Derek: ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GO, LET'S GO.
PULL IT TOGETHER.
Danny: AND EVERYBODY ATE IT UP.
THEY DID WHATEVER
DEREK TOLD THEM TO.
HEY, LET'S GO. COME ON.
WE'RE NOT HERE TO
FUCKING SOCIALIZE.
Man: SHUT THE FUCK UP.
Man: YEAH, MAN.
Man: YOU WANT A LITTLE TOKE?
HUH?
GO AHEAD.
CURTIS, WHAT IS THAT?
AW, COME ON, DEREK.
WEED IS FOR NIGGERS.
PUT THAT AWAY RIGHT NOW.
AW, JESUS FUCKING CHRIST.
HAVE A LITTLE SELF-RESPECT.
Man: YEAH.
ALL RIGHT, LISTEN UP.
WE NEED TO OPEN OUR EYES.
THERE'S OVER 2 MILLION
ILLEGAL IMMIGRANTS
BEDDING DOWN IN
THIS STATE TONIGHT.
THIS STATE SPENT
$3 BILLION LAST YEAR
ON SERVICES FOR THOSE PEOPLE
WHO HAD NO RIGHT TO BE
HERE IN THE FIRST PLACE...
$3 BILLION.
$400 MILLION JUST TO LOCK UP
A BUNCH OF ILLEGAL
IMMIGRANT CRIMINALS
WHO ONLY GOT INTO THIS COUNTRY
BECAUSE THE FUCKING INS DECIDED
IT'S NOT WORTH THE EFFORT TO
SCREEN FOR CONVICTED FELONS.
WHO GIVES A SHIT?
OUR GOVERNMENT
DOESN'T GIVE A SHIT.
OUR BORDER POLICY IS A JOKE,
SO IS ANYBODY SURPRISED
THAT SOUTH OF THE BORDER
THEY'RE LAUGHING AT US?
LAUGHING AT OUR LAWS?
YEAH.
EVERY NIGHT, THOUSANDS
OF THESE PARASITES
STREAM ACROSS THE BORDER
LIKE SOME FUCKING
PIÑATA EXPLODED.
DON'T LAUGH.
THERE'S NOTHING
FUNNY GOING ON HERE.
THIS IS ABOUT
YOUR LIFE AND MINE.
IT'S ABOUT DECENT,
HARD-WORKING AMERICANS
FALLING THROUGH THE
CRACKS AND GETTING THE SHAFT
BECAUSE THEIR GOVERNMENT
CARES MORE ABOUT THE
CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS
OF A BUNCH OF PEOPLE
WHO AREN'T EVEN
CITIZENS OF THIS COUNTRY.
ON THE STATUE
OF LIBERTY IT SAYS,
"GIVE ME YOUR TIRED,
YOUR HUNGRY, YOUR POOR."
WELL, IT'S AMERICANS WHO ARE
TIRED AND HUNGRY AND POOR,
AND I SAY UNTIL YOU
TAKE CARE OF THAT,
CLOSE THE FUCKING BOOK,
BECAUSE WE'RE LOSING.
WE'RE LOSING OUR RIGHT
TO PURSUE OUR DESTINY.
WE'RE LOSING OUR FREEDOM
SO THAT A BUNCH OF
FUCKING FOREIGNERS
CAN COME IN HERE AND
EXPLOIT OUR COUNTRY.
AND THIS ISN'T SOMETHING
THAT'S GOING ON FAR AWAY.
THIS ISN'T SOMETHING
THAT'S HAPPENING
PLACES WE CAN'T DO
ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
IT'S HAPPENING RIGHT HERE...
RIGHT IN OUR NEIGHBORHOOD,
RIGHT IN THAT
BUILDING BEHIND YOU.
ARCHIE MILLER RAN
THAT GROCERY STORE
SINCE WE WERE KIDS HERE.
DAVE WORKED THERE.
MIKE WORKED THERE.
HE WENT UNDER, AND NOW
SOME FUCKING KOREAN OWNS IT,
WHO FIRED THESE GUYS
AND IS MAKING A KILLING
BECAUSE HE HIRED 40
FUCKING BORDER JUMPERS.
I SEE THIS SHIT GOING ON,
AND I DON'T SEE ANYBODY
DOING ANYTHING ABOUT IT,
AND IT FUCKING PISSES ME OFF.
SO LOOK AROUND YOU.
THIS ISN'T OUR FUCKING
NEIGHBORHOOD.
IT'S A BATTLEFIELD.
WE'RE ON A BATTLEFIELD TONIGHT.
MAKE A DECISION.
ARE WE GOING TO
STAND ON THE SIDELINES?
QUIETLY STANDING THERE
WHILE OUR COUNTRY GETS RAPED?
Crowd: NO!
ARE WE GOING TO ANTE UP
AND DO SOMETHING ABOUT IT?
YEAH!
YOU'RE GODDAMN RIGHT, WE ARE.
AAH!
COME HERE!
DON'T YOU KNOW
IT'S AGAINST THE LAW
TO HIRE FUCKING BORDER JUMPERS,
YOU NIP BASTARD?
UHH! UHH! AAH!
HEY, SWEETHEART.
NO, NO, NO. YOU DON'T NEED THIS.
YOU DON'T NEED THIS. WE'RE
NOT GOING TO HURT YOU.
PLEASE, PLEASE! NO!
NO!
AAH! AAH!
YOU FUCKING SPIC!
HA!
NO! PLEASE!
I THINK THIS BITCH DESERVES IT.
OH, MAN, THIS BITCH STINKS.
SHE SMELLS LIKE FISH
AND CHIPS AND GUACAMOLE.
AH, HERE WE GO.
AAH!
Man: AAH! AAH!
GODDAMN!
Man: GET THE FUCK
OFF ME, MOTHERFUCKER!
GO!
GET DOWN!
UHH!
VIVA LA MEXICO!
HAVE A FUCKING BEAN,
YOU FUCKING BEANER!
YEAH!
YOU FUCKING DOGGY DICK!
Man: GET SOME OF
THAT IN THERE. MMM.
THROW IT ON. THROW IT ON.
HEY, THAT'S A GREAT
COLOR ON YOU, YOU KNOW?
NOW YOU CAN GET A
WHITE WOMAN'S JOB, BITCH.
A LITTLE BETTER
THAN THIS ONE, HUH?
YEAH.
WHITE.
THEN YOU'LL MOVE
UP IN THE WORLD, HUH?
YEAH. WHOO!
ASSHOLE!
UHH!
Derek: COME ON, LET'S
GO! WE'RE OUT OF HERE!
EVERYBODY OUT! LET'S GO!
NOW! NOW!
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO! LET'S GO!
COME ON!
COME ON, LET'S GO,
LET'S GO, LET'S GO.
LET'S GO!
NO GREEN CARD, NO FUCKING WORK,
COMPRENDE?
Man: COME ON, COME ON!
Man: GO, GO, GO!
WE'RE FUCKING GOING! COME ON!
Danny: DAD WAS GONE,
BUT THINGS WERE
ALMOST NORMAL AGAIN.
DEREK HAD A GOOD JOB.
MOM WAS STARTING
TO LIVE A LITTLE.
EVERYONE WAS FEELING SO GOOD
THAT WE JUST
DIDN'T SEE IT COMING.
MAYBE WE SHOULD'VE.
THE IRONY IS THAT
MOST OF THE STORES
THAT WERE DESTROYED
DURING THE RIOTS
WERE OWNED BY BLACK PEOPLE.
THAT'S STUPID, THOUGH.
I MEAN, WHY TRASH YOUR
OWN NEIGHBORHOOD?
WELL, THAT'S MY POINT.
IT'S AN IRRATIONAL ACT.
IT'S LIKE AN EXPRESSION OF RAGE
BY PEOPLE WHO FEEL NEGLECTED
AND TURNED AWAY BY THE SYSTEM.
EXACTLY.
I MEAN, IT'S LIKE
WE HAD IN WATTS
OR THE RIOTS IN CHICAGO IN '68.
THAT'S CRAP. I DON'T
BUY THAT FOR A MINUTE.
CALLING A RIOT AN IRRATIONAL
EXPRESSION OF RAGE...
THAT'S SUCH A COP-OUT.
IT'S OPPORTUNISM AT ITS WORST.
IT'S A BUNCH OF PEOPLE
GRABBING ANY
EXCUSE THEY CAN FIND
TO GO AND LOOT A STORE,
NOTHING MORE.
THE FACT THAT THESE
PEOPLE RIPPED OFF THE STORES
IN THEIR OWN COMMUNITIES,
ALL THAT REFLECTS
IS THE DEGREE TO
WHICH THESE PEOPLE
HAVE ABSOLUTELY NO
RESPECT FOR THE LAW AT ALL
AND CERTAINLY NO
CONCEPT OF, LIKE, COMMUNITY
OR... OR CIVIC RESPONSIBILITY.
NOW WAIT A MINUTE.
WHITE PEOPLE COMMIT CRIMES
AGAINST WHITE PEOPLE, TOO.
YEAH, BUT THEY'RE NOT OFFING
EACH OTHER IN RECORD NUMBERS
ALL OVER AMERICA.
LOOK AT THE STATISTICS,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE.
ONE IN EVERY THREE BLACK MALES
IS IN SOME PHASE OF A
CORRECTIONAL SYSTEM.
IS THAT A COINCIDENCE,
OR DO THESE PEOPLE
HAVE, YOU KNOW, LIKE,
A RACIAL COMMITMENT TO CRIME?
WELL, NOT ONLY THAT.
THEY'RE PROUD OF IT.
MAYBE IT SAYS SOMETHING
ABOUT PREJUDICE
IN THE JUDICIAL SYSTEM.
YEAH. IF YOU WANT TO TALK
ABOUT CRIMINAL STATISTICS,
YOU MIGHT WANT TO TAKE A LOOK
AT THE SOCIAL INEQUALITIES
THAT PRODUCE THEM.
YAP, YAP. YOU KNOW WHAT?
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT I HATE,
BECAUSE WHAT YOU'RE
DOING IS TAKING ONE THING
AND CALLING IT SOMETHING ELSE
AND JUST, YOU KNOW,
ALLEVIATING THE RESPONSIBILITY
THAT THESE PEOPLE HAVE
FOR THEIR OWN ACTIONS.
YOU KNOW, IT'S LIKE SAYING,
IT'S NOT A RIOT, IT'S RAGE.
IT'S NOT CRIME, IT'S POVERTY.
THAT'S JUST NONSENSE.
IT'S BULLSHIT.
IT'S EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED IN THIS TRIAL, TOO,
BECAUSE THE MEDIA
TWISTED THINGS AROUND
SO PEOPLE GOT ALL FOCUSED ON,
YOU KNOW, THESE COPS
AND WHETHER OR NOT THEY
WERE GOING TO GET CONVICTED
AND WHETHER RODNEY
KING'S CIVIL RIGHTS
HAD BEEN VIOLATED.
EVERYBODY LOST SIGHT OF
OLD RODNEY KING HIMSELF.
I MEAN, THE GUY'S
A MULTIPLE FELON
BY HIS OWN ADMISSION.
HE'S HIGH AS A GODDAMN KITE
DRIVING 120 MILES AN
HOUR DOWN THE HIGHWAY.
HE GETS PULLED OVER
BY A BUNCH OF COPS,
AND... AND HE ATTACKS THEM.
HE ATTACKED POLICE OFFICERS.
THAT'S THE BOTTOM
LINE, AND HE WALKED.
YEAH, AND THERE'S
SOME YAHOO THERE
WITH A VIDEO CAMERA
WHO TURNED IT ON
HALFWAY THROUGH,
SO THAT ALL WE SEE
IS THEM HITTING HIM.
EXACTLY. YOU GOT POWELL AND KOON
WINDING UP AND CRACKING
HIM WITH BILLY CLUBS
AND BRISENO'S KICKING HIM
IN THE BACK OF THE SKULL,
SO IT LOOKS SEVERE, YOU KNOW?
AND PEOPLE ARE GOING,
"OH, THIS POOR GUY."
THIS POOR GUY WHO
ATTACKED 4 COPS,
AND THOSE COPS
END UP ON THE STAND
DEFENDING THEMSELVES
FOR USING ABSOLUTELY
STANDARD TEXTBOOK
SELF-DEFENSE PROCEDURES.
I DON'T THINK THE TAPES
SHOWED THAT AT ALL.
OH, YOU DIDN'T THINK SO, HUH?
AND, WHAT, YOU'RE
AN AUTHORITY, MA?
MURRAY, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WELL, I... I DID THINK
THAT THE POLICE
USED THEIR CLUBS
RATHER EXCESSIVELY.
WHO ARE YOU TO SAY
WHAT'S EXCESSIVE?
I THINK IT WAS
TOTALLY APPROPRIATE.
I THINK THEY'RE IN
A BETTER POSITION
TO MAKE THAT JUDGMENT
CALL THAN YOU ARE.
IN FACT, WE, AS SOCIETY,
GRANT COPS A CERTAIN
AMOUNT OF AUTHORITY
TO MAKE THOSE CALLS,
BECAUSE WE ACKNOWLEDGE
THAT THEIR JOB IS
DIFFICULT AND DANGEROUS,
YOU KNOW? UNFORTUNATELY,
VERY FEW PEOPLE, LIKE,
RESPECT THAT AND
RESPECT THAT AUTHORITY.
LOOK WHO'S TALKING ABOUT
RESPECT... MR. JUNIOR KKK.
WHAT?
YOU WANT TO GO
TO COLLEGE, DAVINA,
YOU SHOULD LEARN TO LISTEN.
DEREK. DEREK.
I ACKNOWLEDGE A COP'S AUTHORITY.
I DON'T RESPECT ANY LAWS
THAT LET MONKEYS
LIKE RODNEY KING
BACK ON THE STREET.
SECOND OF ALL, I AM
NOT, AS YOU WELL KNOW,
A MEMBER OF A LOW-RENT,
DISORGANIZED BUNCH OF REDNECKS
LIKE THE FUCKING KKK. PLEASE.
SO TAKE YOUR HEAD
OUT OF YOUR ASS.
YOU'VE GOTTEN OFF THE POINT.
I HAD A POINT. THAT
WASN'T EVEN THE POINT.
DO YOU HAVE ONE? WHAT
IS YOUR POINT, DEREK?
ALL RIGHT, THINK ABOUT
THIS. THINK ABOUT THIS.
IF DANNY HAD BEEN WALKING
ACROSS THE STREET THAT NIGHT,
AND RODNEY KING
HAD PLOWED INTO HIM...
CAN WE JUST DROP
THIS RODNEY KING THING?
MM-HMM.
WHO WOULD LIKE SOME DESSERT?
WE'RE HAVING A DISCUSSION.
WE'RE HAVING A NICE
DISCUSSION, RIGHT?
IF RODNEY KING HAD
BEEN DRIVING ALONG
HOPPED UP ON
CHIVAS REGAL AND PCP
AND HAD KILLED DANNY,
YOU'D BE SINGING A
VERY DIFFERENT TUNE...
I DIDN'T SEE HIM HIT ANYBODY,
AND NEITHER DID YOU.
HE DIDN'T HAPPEN
TO KILL ANYBODY,
THANK GOD.
KEEP IT DOWN, OK?
ALLY'S SLEEPING.
IF HE HAD, THOUGH, I MEAN,
COME ON, THINK ABOUT IT.
IF THAT FUCKING MONKEY
HAD RUN SOME KID OVER,
EVERYBODY WOULD HAVE
A VERY DIFFERENT OPINION
OF THIS WHOLE MATTER.
YOU KNOW, THEY'D BE
FOCUSED ON RODNEY KING
AND NOT ON THESE OFFICERS.
BUT INSTEAD,
HE JUST ATTACKED A FEW COPS,
AND SO, ALL THE SUDDEN,
IT'S HANDS ACROSS AMERICA
FOR THIS FUCKING
TOTAL SON OF A BITCH.
I MEAN, IT BLOWS MY MIND.
WE'RE SO HUNG UP ON THIS NOTION
THAT WE HAVE SOME OBLIGATION
TO HELP THIS STRUGGLING
BLACK MAN, YOU KNOW?
CUT HIM SOME SLACK
UNTIL HE CAN OVERCOME
THESE HISTORICAL INJUSTICES.
IT'S CRAP. THIS STUFF
JUST PERPETUATES IT...
ALL THIS LIBERAL
NONSENSE, YOU KNOW?
EVERYONE'S TURNING AND
LOOKING THE OTHER WAY
WHILE OUR COUNTRY
ROTS FROM THE INSIDE OUT.
I MEAN, CHRIST, LINCOLN
FREED THE SLAVES,
WHAT, LIKE, 130 YEARS AGO.
HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE
TO GET YOUR ACT TOGETHER?
JEWS HAVE BEEN PERSECUTED
FOR OVER 5,000 YEARS.
ARE YOU SAYING THAT IT'S
WRONG TO FEEL SENSITIVE
ABOUT ANTI-SEMITISM?
Stacey: OH, FORGET THAT.
I'M WITH YOU. I'M WITH
YOU ALL THE WAY, BABY.
I'M SO SICK OF THESE
LIBERAL HYPOCRITES.
OH, HERE WE GO
AGAIN. I LOVE THIS PART.
THIS IS GREAT.
LOOK AT THE WAY THEY
SCAPEGOATED CHIEF GATES.
YOU TELL ME THEY WOULD'VE
COME DOWN THAT HARD
ON BLACK WILLIE WILLIAMS.
NO WAY, BECAUSE THAT
VIDEOTAPE WAS A SET-UP
TO GET RID OF GATES.
YES.
NO. NO, YOU CANNOT.
DON'T INTERRUPT.
EXCUSE ME. I WAS
TALKING. I LISTENED TO YOU.
WHO DO YOU DON'T THINK
YOU ARE? INTERRUPT.
SHE'S RIGHT IN THE
MIDDLE OF MAKING A POINT.
WHO THE HELL DO
YOU THINK YOU ARE?
HEY! DAVINA, SIT DOWN.
SIT DOWN! BE QUIET! SHUT UP!
SIT DOWN! NO!
DEREK, SHUT UP! CALM DOWN.
DON'T TELL ME TO SHUT UP!
SIT YOUR ASS DOWN.
NO. SIT DOWN. SHUT YOUR MOUTH.
MOVE! NO!
GOD DAMN IT, DEREK! MOVE!
SHUT YOUR MOUTH AND
GIVE MY GIRLFRIEND RESPECT.
DEREK, WHAT ARE
YOU TRYING TO PROVE?
MURRAY, STAY OUT
OF IT! COME HERE!
HEY, WHERE DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE GOING?
Murray: DEREK, LET HER GO!
DEREK, LET HER GO!
YOU NEED TO LEARN SOME
FUCKING MANNERS, DAVINA!
SHUT YOUR FUCKING MOUTH!
SHUT UP!
Doris: STOP!
SHE CAN'T BREATHE!
Derek: UHH!
LET HER GO!
YOU GOING TO APOLOGIZE?
ARE YOU GOING TO APOLOGIZE?
YOU'RE ARE YOU? AN ASSHOLE.
AAH! I HATE YOU!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING,
DEREK? THIS IS YOUR FAMILY.
RIGHT. MY FAMILY. MY FAMILY,
SO YOU KNOW WHAT?
I DON'T GIVE 2 SHITS ABOUT YOU
OR ANYBODY ELSE
OR WHAT YOU THINK.
YOU'RE NOT A PART OF
IT, AND YOU NEVER WILL BE.
THAT HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH IT.
OH, IT DOESN'T?
YOU DON'T THINK I SEE WHAT
YOU'RE TRYING TO DO HERE?
YOU THINK I'M GOING
TO SIT HERE AND SMILE
WHILE SOME FUCKING KIKE
TRIES TO FUCK MY MOTHER?
IT'S NEVER GOING
TO HAPPEN, MURRAY.
FUCKING FORGET IT.
NOT ON MY WATCH. NOT
WHILE I'M IN THIS FAMILY.
I WILL FUCKING CUT
YOUR SHYLOCK NOSE OFF
AND STICK IT UP YOUR ASS
BEFORE I LET THAT HAPPEN,
COMING IN HERE AND
POISONING MY FAMILY'S DINNER
WITH YOUR JEWISH, NIGGER-LOVING,
HIPPIE BULLSHIT.
FUCK YOU.
FUCK YOU!
YEAH, WALK OUT.
ASSHOLE. FUCKING
CABALA-READING MOTHERFUCKER.
GET THE FUCK OUT OF MY HOUSE.
YOU SEE THIS? THAT
MEANS NOT WELCOME.
WHAT DID I DO?
YOU DISGUST ME, YOU KNOW THAT?
YOU DISGUST ME...
BRING HIM TO OUR TABLE
AND CRIMPING YOUR
HAIR AND YOUR DRESS...
DON'T WHAT DID I DO? TOUCH ME.
WHAT DID I DO TO YOU?
HOW COULD YOU BRING
HIM TO MY FATHER'S TABLE?
HOW COULD YOU GO
FROM DAD TO THAT?
AREN'T YOU ASHAMED?
I'M ASHAMED THAT YOU
CAME OUT OF MY BODY!
GO RUN TO YOUR FUCKING KIKE!
GO RUN TO HIM!
IT'S OK.
I'M PROUD OF YOU, BABY.
I'M SO SORRY, DORIS.
I REALLY AM.
HE'S GONE.
HE'S JUST A BOY
WITHOUT A FATHER.
DORIS,
YOU DON'T KNOW THE WORLD
YOUR CHILDREN ARE LIVING IN.
GOOD-BYE.
HEY, YOU ALL RIGHT?
TAKE THIS, YOU FUCKING DICK!
AAH! NO, NO, NO. COME HERE.
FUCK YOU!
DAVINA, CALM DOWN.
LET GO OF ME! CALM DOWN.
LET ME GO, GOD DAMN IT!
SORRY. FUCK YOU!
I'M SORRY.
I WOULD NEVER HURT
YOU. YOU KNOW THAT.
COME ON. I SCREWED
UP. I LOST CONTROL.
IT'S NOT YOU.
I'M SORRY.
COME ON. I'D NEVER
HURT YOU GUYS.
I'D NEVER HURT
YOU. YOU KNOW THAT.
I'D DO ANYTHING FOR YOU.
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
I TRUST YOU, DEREK.
HI.
HI. WHAT ARE YOU
DOING OUT OF BED, HUH?
YOU WANT A PLANE RIDE?
YEAH.
GOING FOR TAKEOFF.
WHOO-HOO! WHOO!
Danny: OH, NO.
OH, NO, NO. CRASH.
WHOO-HOO!
BETTER GO TO MOM.
OOH, SHE'S A CRAZY FLIER.
KISS MOM.
OH, YEAH.
OK.
OH, YOU DON'T FEEL TOO HOT.
NO. IT'S MY CHEST.
SO, WHAT ARE YOU UP TO?
I'M JUST THINKING.
YEAH.
THERE'S A LOT OF
THAT GOING AROUND.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW HOW
WE GOT HERE SOMETIMES.
MOM...
I FEEL LIKE I LET YOU ALL DOWN,
ONLY I DIDN'T EVEN
KNOW WHEN IT HAPPENED.
MOM, IT'S OK.
YEAH? YEAH.
IT'S COLD IN HERE. NO
WONDER YOU'RE SICK.
NO. YOU DON'T GET
SICK FROM THE COLD.
YOU GET SICK FROM GERMS.
NO. YOU GET SICK FROM SMOKING.
YOU OUGHT TO QUIT.
IT'S NOT GOOD FOR YOU.
WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING
AT ME LIKE THAT FOR?
WHEN ARE YOU GOING TO LET
THAT BEAUTIFUL HAIR GROW BACK?
THE DAY YOU QUIT SMOKING.
DEAL.
I'D BETTER GET ALLY TO BED.
YOU SAY GOOD NIGHT TO MOM?
MM-HMM.
THEN YOU HAVE TO GO TO BED.
COME ON.
GOOD NIGHT, MAMA.
GOOD NIGHT, BABY.
Danny: ALL RIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT, MAMA.
Danny: I GO BACK TO THAT NIGHT
AGAIN AND AGAIN IN MY MIND.
I TRY TO STOP IT FROM HAPPENING.
I WANT YOU OUT OF THIS HOUSE.
THAT'S FINE. I'LL BE
GONE IN THE MORNING.
Stacey: HE CAN MOVE IN WITH ME.
Danny: IN MY MIND, I IMAGINE
WHAT WOULD'VE HAPPENED
IF I HADN'T GONE TO THAT ROOM
AND TOLD HIM.
GET DOWN!
NO, DEREK!
HELP, MOMMY!
AAH!
NIGGER, YOU JUST FUCKED
WITH THE WRONG BULL.
COME HERE!
DAMN! AAH!
YOU SHOULD'VE LEARNED YOUR PLACE
ON THE FUCKING BASKETBALL COURT,
BUT YOU FUCKING MONKEYS
NEVER GET THE MESSAGE!
UHH!
MY FATHER GAVE ME THAT
TRUCK, YOU MOTHERFUCKER!
YOU EVER SHOOT AT FIREMEN?
YOU COME HERE, YOU
SHOOT AT MY FAMILY?
I'M GOING TO TEACH YOU A REAL
LESSON NOW, MOTHERFUCKER.
PUT YOUR FUCKING
MOUTH ON THE CURB.
HOLD ON, MAN.
PUT IT ON THE CURB RIGHT NOW!
Derek: THAT'S IT.
DEREK, NO!
AAH!
NO!
NOW SAY GOOD NIGHT.
AAH!
FUCKER.
DROP YOUR WEAPON!
PUT YOUR WEAPON ON THE GROUND!
PUT YOUR HANDS UP!
I SAID GET YOUR HANDS UP!
NOW TURN AROUND!
PUT YOUR HANDS BEHIND YOUR HEAD!
GET DOWN ON YOUR
KNEES RIGHT NOW!
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GO.
COME ON.
NO.
WHAT, SHE AIN'T
GONNA OPEN THE DOOR?
SOMEONE RIGHT FUCKING
THERE LOOKING AT US. HELLO?
DANNY, IT'S FOR YOU.
BE RIGHT THERE.
WACKA! HA HA!
OPEN THE DOOR, DANNY.
IT'S FUCKING FREEZING!
DANNY, I'M GONNA BE SICK!
WAAH! COME ON, DANNY!
I'M GONNA GO GET SOME BEERS.
HEY, WHAT A PARTY, HUH, FATSO?
I'M NOT FAT, ASSHOLE! I'M HUSKY!
WHAT THE FUCK'S UP, SETH?
DRINK UP, DANNY, BEFORE
YOUR BROTHER SEES YOU.
HOLY FUCK, HE'S HERE!
YEAH, HE'S FUCKING HERE.
GO PAY YOUR RESPECTS.
FUCK YOU, SETH!
LET'S GO TALK TO CAMERON, DANNY.
FATHER VINYARD?
HOW'S IT GOING? I'M
JASON, THIS IS CHRIS.
WE'RE FRIENDS WITH YOUR BROTHER.
YOU ARE A FUCKING GOD, MAN!
Stacey: DEREK!
AAH! HEY.
I THOUGHT YOU
TURNED THAT PAPER IN.
I DID. NOW FUCKING
MURRAY TURNED ME IN,
SO SWEENEY'S MAKING
ME WRITE ANOTHER ONE.
HMM.
GOOD OLD SWEENEY.
HE NEVER STOPS TRYING.
HE'S ONE OF THOSE "PROUD
TO BE NIGGER" PEOPLE.
I HATE THOSE GUYS.
WAIT A MINUTE,
DANNY. HE'S NOT PROUD.
NO.
HE'S A MANIPULATIVE,
SELF-RIGHTEOUS UNCLE TOM.
HE'S TRYING TO
MAKE YOU FEEL GUILTY
ABOUT WRITING
ABOUT ADOLF HITLER.
YEAH. SOME NIGGER,
SOME SPIC WRITES
ABOUT MARTIN LUTHER KING
OR FUCKING CESAR COMMIE CHAVEZ
GETS A PAT ON THE HEAD.
YEAH.
YOU CAN SEE THE
HYPOCRISY IN THAT, CAN'T YOU?
DEFINITELY.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
NO. LISTEN, LISTEN. WAIT.
I WANT TO SEE YOU, OK?
I DO, BUT I GOTTA TAKE
CARE OF SOMETHING TONIGHT.
OK.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
YEAH. I'M HERE.
WHEN YOU'RE READY, I'M HERE.
WOULD YOU DO SOMETHING WITH ME?
ANYTHING.
LEAVE WITH ME.
LEAVE WHERE?
LEAVE HERE. LEAVE ALL THIS.
JUST COME WITH ME.
WHY WOULD YOU WANT TO LEAVE?
THEY WORSHIP YOU.
YOU'RE LIKE A GOD TO THEM.
IF YOU THINK WE
HAD IT GOOD BEFORE,
WAIT TILL YOU SEE
WHAT IT'S LIKE NOW.
LISTEN, I DON'T WANT ALL THAT.
I DON'T WANT IT. I DON'T
WANT MY FAMILY INVOLVED.
EVERYTHING I'VE DONE HERE
FUCKED IT ALL UP, UNDERSTAND?
YOU THINK WHAT
YOU DID WAS WRONG?
OH, BABY. OH, COME ON.
THOSE NIGGERS GOT
EXACTLY WHAT THEY DESERVED,
AND WE ALL KNOW THAT.
I UNDERSTAND YOU JUST GOT OUT,
BUT NO ONE'S GONNA HURT
YOU. NO ONE CAN TOUCH YOU.
THERE'S A SMALL ARMY.
WE'RE NOT GONNA LET A
BUNCH OF SPOOKS KICK US OUT.
STACEY, YOU'RE
NOT LISTENING TO ME.
I'M NOT SCARED. I
DON'T WANT IT ANYMORE.
I'M DONE WITH IT. I'M
THROUGH WITH THIS.
IT'S... IT'S BULLSHIT, STACEY.
YOU DON'T NEED THIS,
STACEY. COME ON, TRUST ME.
IF YOU WANT TO BE WITH ME,
JUST TRUST ME. COME WITH ME.
COME ON.
YOU'RE NUTS. YOU ARE NUTS.
NO WAY.
I DON'T THINK YOU REALIZE
WHAT'S BEEN GOING ON HERE.
WE ARE 10 TIMES WHAT WE WERE,
AND WE ARE BLOODY ORGANIZED.
IT IS LIKE NOTHING
YOU HAVE EVER SEEN.
THIS WAS A MISTAKE. FORGET IT.
WAIT A SECOND.
WHAT WAS A MISTAKE?
STACEY, JUST SAY GOOD-BYE.
THIS ISN'T YOU. I KNOW YOU.
YOU DON'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT ME, STACEY.
HEY, ARE YOU DANNY'S BROTHER?
YEAH.
WILL YOU TELL HIM
LIZZY'S LOOKING FOR HIM?
THANK YOU.
WE'LL LET THE NIGGERS,
KIKES, AND SPICS
GRAB FOR THEIR PIECE OF THE PIE.
CAN'T BLAME 'EM.
COURSE, THEY'RE GONNA
HAVE TO FIGHT TO GET IT.
AND IF WE SCARE THE
FUCK OUT OF PEOPLE,
AND A FEW PEOPLE GET
KILLED IN THE PROCESS,
SO BE IT.
Derek: GONNA PUT THAT
IN YOUR PAPER, DANNY?
HEY, MAN.
WELL, LOOK WHO'S HERE.
THE RETURN OF THE SOLDIER.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE, DANNY?
COME ON, MAN. I
HAD TO CHECK IT OUT.
YOU KNEW I WAS GONNA COME.
LET THE KID ALONE, DEREK.
HE KNOWS WHEN TO GO TO BED.
GO WAIT OUTSIDE.
COME ON, DER. I'M
NOT DOING ANYTHING.
THIS LITTLE BLONDE GIRL
KEEPS ASKING FOR YOU.
SHE'S DYING. COME ON.
WELL, I GOTTA CHECK OUT.
GO EASY ON HER.
ALL RIGHT.
WAIT FOR ME RIGHT OUTSIDE.
TAKE IT EASY.
CHILL OUT.
YOU'RE ON SAFE GROUND.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO WATCH
YOUR ASS AROUND HERE.
COME ON. SIT DOWN. RELAX.
I'M SORRY. THE PARTY
WAS A LITTLE QUICK,
BUT WE'RE JUST SO DAMN
GLAD YOU'RE BACK, DEREK.
IT'S ONLY NATURAL YOU
SHOULD FEEL A LITTLE FUNNY.
I DON'T FEEL FUNNY, CAM.
YOU KNOW, YOU MADE THE
FAT KID A LITTLE NERVOUS.
HE THINKS THE JOINT
MESSED WITH YOUR MIND.
IT DID.
♪♪ GLORY, GLORY, HALLELUJAH ♪♪
♪♪ THE WHITE MAN MARCHES ON ♪♪
THINGS HAVE CHANGED
SINCE YOU'VE BEEN GONE.
YOU TALK ABOUT ORGANIZATION?
WAIT'LL YOU SEE WHAT WE'VE
DONE WITH THE INTERNET.
WE'VE GOT EVERY GANG
FROM SEATTLE TO SAN DIEGO
WORKING TOGETHER NOW.
NOT COMPETING ANYMORE.
THEY'RE CONSOLIDATED.
ONLY THING WE LACK IS A
LITTLE OVERALL LEADERSHIP.
THAT'S WHERE YOU COME IN.
THOSE PEOPLE OUT THERE
GOT A LOT OF RESPECT FOR YOU.
WHEN YOU'RE READY,
COME TALK TO ME ABOUT IT.
WELL, YOU CAN FORGET ABOUT THAT.
I'M DONE WITH IT, CAM.
YEAH, WELL, I KNOW
YOU GREW OUT OF
THAT SHAVED HEAD BULLSHIT
A LONG TIME AGO, THANK GOD.
I LIKE YOUR HAIR
THE WAY IT IS NOW.
SEE, THAT'S WHAT I MEAN.
WE'RE THINKING BIGGER NOW.
NO MORE OF THIS
FUCKING GROCERY STORE...
YOU'RE NOT LISTENING
TO ME. I AM DONE WITH IT.
ALL THAT BULLSHIT OUT THERE
AND ALL YOUR BULLSHIT, TOO.
I'M OUT.
I UNDERSTAND HOW YOU FEEL.
YOU'VE JUST DONE HARD TIME.
DON'T YOU FUCKING TALK
TO ME ABOUT HARD TIME.
YOU DON'T KNOW A THING ABOUT IT.
I'VE DONE MINE.
YOU DIDN'T DO SHIT. I
FOUND OUT ABOUT YOU.
YOU DID 2 MONTHS,
THEN ROLLED OVER ON 2 KIDS
AND LET THEM GO DOWN FOR YOU.
SO DON'T FEED ME YOUR
FUCKING LIES, CAMERON.
ALL RIGHT. THIS IS STUPID.
I'M DONE.
YOU GO COOL OFF. GET
LAID. DO SOMETHING.
GET YOUR HEAD ON STRAIGHT,
AND THEN I'LL TALK TO YOU.
BUT IT DOESN'T MATTER
IF I DON'T, DOES IT?
'CAUSE YOU GOT THE NEXT CROP
LINED UP AND READY TO GO,
YOU FUCKING CHICKEN HAWK.
EXCUSE ME?
YOU PREY ON PEOPLE,
CAM! YOU USE THEM!
I LOST 3 YEARS FOR YOUR
PHONY FUCKING CAUSE,
BUT I AM ON TO YOU
NOW, YOU FUCKING SNAKE.
HEY, DEREK, WATCH
IT. BE CAREFUL.
REMEMBER WHERE YOU ARE.
THIS IS NOT SOME
FUCKING COUNTRY CLUB
WHERE YOU CAN WALTZ
IN AND OUT OF HERE...
SHUT UP! SHUT THE FUCK UP!
I CAME IN HERE TO TELL
YOU ONE THING. I AM OUT.
OUT! AND DANNY IS OUT, TOO!
IF YOU COME NEAR MY
FAMILY, I'LL FUCKING KILL YOU.
WELL, EXCUSE ME,
BUT FUCK YOU, DEREK.
YOU CAN'T COME
BARKING THREATS AT ME.
YOU CAN DO WHATEVER YOU
WANT, BUT DANNY IS A GOOD KID.
HE'S NOT SOME
WHINY PUSSY LIKE YOU.
HE NEEDS MY HELP, AND
I'M GONNA GIVE IT TO HIM.
IF YOU COME NEAR DANNY AGAIN,
I WILL FEED YOU YOUR
FUCKING HEART, CAMERON.
I WON'T HAVE TO.
HE'LL COME TO ME.
I'M MORE IMPORTANT TO HIM
NOW THAN YOU'LL EVER BE.
UNH!
SHIT.
YOU'RE A FUCKING
DEAD MAN, VINYARD.
HEY, HEY, HEY. WHERE'S CAMERON?
WHERE THE FUCK IS HE?
HEY, DEREK.
HEY, DEREK!
STAY AWAY FROM ME. DANNY!
WHY DON'T YOU SHARE
WITH THE REST OF US
WHAT YOU JUST SAID TO ME,
YOU PIECE OF SHIT NIGGER!
YOU MONKEY-FUCKING
DANNY! TRAITOR!
YOU A FUCKING NIGGER-FUCKER?
HEY, DANNY! COME ON!
HE'S A FUCKING
NIGGER! NIGGER! NIGGER!
CAM'S OUT COLD! WHERE
THE FUCK ARE YOU GOING?
Skinhead: GUN! HE'S GOT A GUN!
SHIT! BACK UP!
Danny: SETH!
YOU MAKE ME FUCKING SICK!
SETH! PUT DOWN THE FUCKING GUN!
Man: SHOOT THE NIGGER!
SHOOT HIM! DO IT, SETH! DO IT!
Woman: TRAITOR!
SETH!
DO IT, SETH! DO IT!
AAH!
BACK UP! MOVE!
BACK UP! BACK THE FUCK UP!
MOVE! MOVE!
Man: EASY, DEREK! HEY!
EASY, DANNY!
FUCK YOU! WHO DO
YOU THINK YOU ARE?!
DANNY, RELAX.
WHO DO YOU THINK YOU ARE?
TAKE IT EASY, DAN. TAKE IT EASY.
I FUCKING HATE YOU, DER!
ALL RIGHT, SHH, SHH. I MEAN IT.
HUH?
COME ON. SHUT UP. TAKE IT EASY.
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO YOU, DER?
TAKE IT EASY. TAKE IT EASY.
COME ON. COME ON.
Danny: IT'S JUST SO FUCKED.
I'M SORRY. YOU WEREN'T
SUPPOSED TO SEE THAT.
I TOLD YOU NOT TO COME.
FUCK YOU, MAN.
THAT WAS SO FUCKED UP.
I KNOW, I KNOW.
GOD, IT WASN'T SUPPOSED
TO HAPPEN THAT WAY.
THAT WAS FUCKED UP.
THAT'S ALL THERE IS TO IT.
THAT'S NOT WHAT I PLANNED.
IT JUST ALL WENT TO SHIT.
JUST SHIT. GOT TOTALLY
OUT OF CONTROL.
WHAT'S FUCKING HAPPENING HERE?
HEY, LOOK AT ME.
I CAN'T GO BACK TO THAT, DAN.
CAN'T GO BACK TO WHAT?
TO ANY OF IT.
THOSE GUYS, THE GANG,
THAT LIFE... I'M DONE WITH IT.
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU UP THERE?
Guard: FEED LINE.
BACK UP FOR CHOW.
DON'T BE LATE,
YOU PIECE OF SHIT!
LET'S GO IF YOU WANT TO EAT!
GET UP! 5 MINUTES!
THIS IS MY FUCKING
HOUSE! GET UP!
WHAT THE FUCK'S YOUR
PROBLEM, YOU ASSHOLES?
MOVE!
LET'S GO! OPEN
THE FUCKING GATES!
ALL RIGHT, RACK 'EM!
5 MINUTES! STEP FORWARD!
THOSE BEDS BETTER BE MADE.
Derek: AFTER 2
DAYS IN THAT PLACE,
I DIDN'T THINK I WAS
GONNA MAKE IT A WEEK.
Guard: COME ON,
YOU MOTHERFUCKERS!
YOU WANT TO EAT TODAY,
YOU FUCKING PIECE OF SHIT?
HEY, YOU WHITE
TRASH PIECE OF SHIT!
YOU THINK YOU'RE FUCKING
SPECIAL, WHITEFISH?
BUTTON THAT TOP
BUTTON! LET'S GO! MOVE!
ARE YOU EYEBALLING ME?
DON'T EYEBALL-FUCK ME, ASSHOLE!
I'LL FUCKING KILL YOU!
I'M GONNA KEEP MY EYE ON
YOU, YOU WHITE PIECE OF SHIT!
DON'T FUCKING EYEBALL ME,
BOY! I'LL FUCKING SKULL-FUCK YOU!
STEP FORWARD!
TURN TO THE LEFT.
STEP FORWARD TO CHOW! LET'S GO!
COME ON! HEY, FISH,
STRAIGHT AHEAD.
STRAIGHT AHEAD,
FUCKER! LET'S GO!
Derek: ALL THE WRONG PEOPLE
KNEW WHO I WAS ANYWAY,
SO I FIGURED I'D PUT UP A
FLAG AND HOPE A FRIEND SEES IT.
THAT'S THE CAT I'M
TALKING ABOUT RIGHT THERE.
BOSS. HEY.
HAVE A SEAT.
HEY.
IT'S A PLEASURE.
DON'T FUCK WITH ME, ALL RIGHT?
'CAUSE I'M THE MOST
DANGEROUS MAN IN THIS PRISON.
YOU KNOW WHY?
'CAUSE I CONTROL THE UNDERWEAR.
WE PICK 'EM UP OVER HERE,
AND WE STORE 'EM OVER THERE.
AND I HOPE YOU
WORK OUT, ALL RIGHT?
'CAUSE THE LAST GUY THEY SENT
ME DIDN'T WEAR NO DRAWERS,
COULDN'T READ THE
SIZES IN THE DRAWERS,
AND USED TO SNIFF THE
DRAWERS, ALL RIGHT?
WE GOT 2 SIZES... MEDIUM
AND LARGE, ALL RIGHT?
ALL YOU GOTTA DO IS PUT THE
MEDIUMS WITH THE MEDIUMS
AND THE LARGES WITH
THE LARGES, ALL RIGHT?
I KNOW IT'S A BORING JOB,
BUT IT'S BETTER THAN THAT
LAST SHIT THEY HAD ME DOING.
I SPENT 2 YEARS IN THE KITCHEN
SCRUBBIN' HOT-ASS POTS AND PANS.
THAT YOU DON'T
WANNA DO, ALL RIGHT?
YOU SHOULD BE HAPPY AS
SHIT YOU LANDED THIS JOB.
THERE'S NO TELLING
WHAT THEY'D HAVE YOU DO
UP IN THE JOINT.
BY THE WAY, UH...
WHAT YOU IN FOR?
PROBABLY ROBBED
SOME OLD LADY, HUH?
OK, I KNOW YOUR KIND, RIGHT?
BAD-ASS PECKERWOOD
WITH AN ATTITUDE.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING, MAN,
YOU BETTER WATCH YOUR ASS,
'CAUSE IN THE JOINT,
YOU THE NIGGER, NOT ME.
Derek: I WAS A YEAR IN. I
THOUGHT I WAS CRUISING.
THEN EVERYTHING STARTED
GETTING COMPLICATED.
WHAT THE FUCK IS THAT?
Derek: WHAT'S THAT ALL ABOUT?
THAT'S JUST POLITICS,
MAN. FAVORS, YOU KNOW?
HE'S DOING FAVORS
FOR THAT FUCKING SPIC?
MITCH HAS JUST GOT A
LITTLE SOMETHING EXTRA
ON THE SIDE WITH
THEM BOYS, YOU KNOW?
YOU'RE KIDDING, RIGHT?
NO.
THAT'S BULLSHIT, MAN.
SOMEBODY SHOULD
SAY SOMETHING TO HIM.
WHAT THE FUCK IS HE THINKING?
MITCH IS THE ONLY REASON
YOU'RE NOT A CORPSE RIGHT NOW.
YOU KNOW WHAT? I
DON'T FUCKING GIVE A SHIT.
I CAN TAKE CARE OF MYSELF.
HE SHOULDN'T BE DOING THAT.
I'M GETTING SICK OF IT, MAN.
THERE'S A LOT OF HARD TALK
HERE AND NO FOLLOW-THROUGH.
I THINK YOU BETTER CHILL OUT
ON THE PREACHING BULLSHIT.
WE'RE GETTING A LITTLE TIRED
OF THAT SHIT AROUND HERE.
EASE UP ON IT.
YO.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE, DORIS?
I WAS IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
LOOK, I TOLD YOU I DON'T
WANT YOU ALL COMING UP HERE.
I DON'T CARE WHAT
YOU TOLD ME, OK?
I NEED TO TALK TO YOU NOW.
SO, HOW IS EVERYONE?
DAVINA'S GREAT. SHE'S
GETTING STRAIGHT As ALMOST.
AND, UH, ALLY'S WALKING,
STARTING TO TALK A LITTLE.
HOW'S DANNY?
DANNY?
DANNY...
HE HOLDS YOU UP SO HIGH.
HE THINKS YOU'RE THE GREATEST.
HE'S ALWAYS BRAGGING
ABOUT YOU TO CAMERON...
AND ALL HIS NEW FRIENDS.
HE'S STARTING TO
REMIND ME OF YOU.
JESUS, DON'T SOUND
SO WORRIED, ALL RIGHT?
I'M SURE HE'S FINE.
HE'S 16 YEARS OLD, DORIS.
HE'S NOT GONNA BE A
LITTLE ANGEL FOREVE.
YOU THINK BECAUSE I
WATCHED MY FIRSTBORN
FUCK UP HIS ENTIRE
LIFE THAT I CAN SIT HERE
AND WATCH MY BABY FOLLOW
HIM DOWN THE SAME TOILET?
I CAN'T FIX ALL THIS
SHIT FROM UP HERE.
I'M NOT ASKING YOU TO.
ALL IT DOES IS MAKE ME FEEL BAD.
YOU'RE JUST MAKING IT HARDER.
YOU THINK YOU'RE THE
ONLY ONE DOING TIME, DEREK?
YOU THINK YOU'RE HERE ALL ALONE?
YOU THINK I'M NOT
IN HERE WITH YOU?
FUCK, MAN.
EVERY DAY I WATCH YOU
GO THROUGH THESE SHEETS
LIKE YOU GONNA GET
TO THE END OF THEM.
LOOK, NIGGER, WILL
YOU CHILL THE FUCK OUT?
GODDAMN!
NO MATTER HOW FAST
YOU GET THROUGH THEM,
THEY GONNA KEEP BRINGING THEM IN
AND BRINGING THEM IN.
AND THROWING THEM
AROUND LIKE THAT
AIN'T GONNA DO A DAMN THING
BUT GIVE YOU A HEART ATTACK!
AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
THAT'S COOL WITH ME!
BUT YOU GONNA GIVE ME A
GODDAMN HEART ATTACK, TOO!
I KNOW, I'M JUST A DUMB,
STUPID NIGGER, RIGHT?
WHAT DO I KNOW?
I KNOW I AIN'T THE ONE
GETTING MAD AT THEM
DAMN SHEETS, THOUGH.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
THE ONLY SHEETS I GET MAD AT...
I'LL TELL YOU.
ALL RIGHT, BOY, THIS
IS WHAT WE GONNA DO.
WE GONNA HATE SOME NIGGERS.
THAT'S WHAT WE'LL DO TODAY.
WE GONNA HATE SOME
GODDAMN NIGGERS.
THAT'S ALL WE GONNA DO IS
HATE SOME NIGGERS ALL DAY.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT A NIGGER IS,
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
WE GONNA HATE THEM.
MY COUSIN DEREK IS
IN THE PEN RIGHT NOW
WORKIN' NEXT TO A NIGGER,
DRIVING HIM NIGGER CRAZY.
SEE?
THAT'S THE TICKET.
NICE AND EASY.
NOW WE CAN IGNORE
EACH OTHER IN PEACE.
"WHAT ARE YOU DOING?"
YOU KNOW WHAT HE TELLS ME?
"IT'S BETTER THAN THE
PIG I JUST TRIED TO FUCK."
HE NEVER LETS
ME FINISH THE JOKE.
YOU FUCK HIM, TOO?
WHATEVER. I GET BACK,
SHE'S LAYING ON HER BACK,
HER LEGS ARE OPEN...
WHAT'S UP?
HOW YOU DOING?
THERE YOU GO.
Derek: HE WAS TAKING
IT FROM THE MEXICANS
AND DEALING IT OUT
TO HIS OWN PEOPLE.
HE DIDN'T BELIEVE IN SHIT.
NONE OF THEM DID.
HEY!
HEY, VINYARD!
WHAT?
COME ON, MAN.
DON'T LOOK AT ME LIKE THAT.
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT
SMELLS LIKE, RIGHT?
DON'T TELL ME THIS SMELL
DON'T REMIND YOU OF A WOMAN.
GOD, I MISS THAT SMELL, MAN.
I MEAN, THE JOB I
HAD ON THE OUTSIDE
WASN'T MUCH
BETTER THAN THIS ONE,
BUT AT LEAST I GOT TO
GO HOME EVERY NIGHT
AND LIE DOWN NEXT TO
THAT SWEET SMELL, MAN.
GOD, I MISS THAT.
YOU GOT A WOMAN?
YEAH, YOU GOT A WOMAN, MAN.
LET ME GIVE YOU SOME
ADVICE, ALL RIGHT?
WHEN SHE COMES TO VISIT YOU...
WHATEVER YOU DO, NO MATTER WHAT,
DON'T LET HER LEAVE
HERE IN A FIGHT, MAN.
DON'T LET HER WALK
OUT WITH A BAD ATTITUDE,
'CAUSE IF YOU DO,
YOU SPEND THE NEXT WEEK
WONDER IF SHE'S GETTING HER
FUCK ON WITH SOMEBODY ELSE,
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING?
SO WHEN SHE COME TO SEE
YOU, IT'S NOTHING BUT SWEET TALK.
SEND HER AWAY
FLOATING, ALL RIGHT?
'CAUSE IT'S NOT
LIKE THE REAL WORLD
WHERE YOU CAN FIGHT,
BUT IT'S COOL TO FIGHT,
'CAUSE YOU CAN MAKE UP
AND HAVE THAT MAKE-UP SEX.
KNOW WHAT I'M
SAYING? THAT ANGRY SEX.
THAT SEX WITH AN ATTITUDE.
WHERE YOU JUST LAY ON YOUR BACK
AND LET HER TAKE OUT ALL
THAT AGGRESSION ON YOU.
ALL GUYS KNOW THAT, MAN.
THAT'S THAT GOOD SEX.
THAT'S THAT POW, POW, POW.
LET HER GET ON TOP,
AND SHE'S GONNA
PUNISH YOU FIRST, RIGHT?
"YOU BEEN A BAD BOY, HUH?
"YOU BEEN A BAD BOY,
AND I'M GONNA PUNISH YOU.
"I'M GONNA PUT IT ON YOU.
DON'T YOU EVER... LET...
ME... CATCH... YOU..."
"LOOKING AT... ANOTHER... WOMAN.
"YEAH, YEAH.
"I MAY FORGIVE
YOU IF YOU BRING IT.
"I THINK I CAN...
I... I FORGIVE.
"I FORGIVE. OH, RIGHT THERE.
"RIGHT THERE. YOU'RE HITTING IT.
"MY SPOT. THAT'S
IT. RIGHT. YEAH.
"YES, YES. I FOR...
I FORGIVE YOU.
"I FORGIVE YOU.
"I FOR... I FOR... I
FOR... I FORGIVE YOU!
I LOVE YOU!"
HOW DO YOU FIGURE THE LAKERS
TO EVER BE A BIGGER DYNASTY
THAN THE CELTICS?
THE LAKERS ARE LIKE
A FLARE-UP, A FLUKE,
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
ARE YOU CRAZY?
ONE GOOD COACH FOR 4 YEARS.
THE CELTICS ARE A DYNASTY!
AW, COME ON, MAN.
THE CELTICS, RIGHT?
THE UGLIEST TEAM IN
THE HISTORY OF SPORTS.
A DYNASTY OF UGLY
MOTHERFUCKERS, MAN.
LOOK AT KEVIN McHALE.
JAMES WORTHY.
THEY GUY HAS A
HEAD LIKE A MELON.
NO, HE HAD LADIES.
I CAN'T EVEN TALK TO YOU.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
YOU ARE TWEAKING.
BOSTON CELTICS.
HOW MANY IS THAT?
THAT'S ENOUGH.
ENOUGH? ALL RIGHT.
YOU GOT THAT?
I LOST COUNT, MAN.
DOESN'T MATTER, MAN.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
WHO'S COUNTING ANYWAY?
ALL RIGHT, SO I WANNA
KNOW SOMETHING.
WHAT THE FUCK
LANDED YOU IN HERE?
YOU DIDN'T KILL ANYBODY, TOO
SKINNY FOR A GANGBANGER...
OH, AIN'T THAT A BITCH?
DON'T JUDGE A BOOK
BY ITS COVER, MAN.
I CAN THROW THESE
THINGS, ALL RIGHT?
YEAH. WHATEVER, WHATEVER.
COME ON. WHAT'D YOU DO?
NONE OF YOUR
BUSINESS, ALL RIGHT?
IT'S EMBARRASSING, ALL RIGHT?
IT'S NONE OF YOUR
GODDAMN BUSINESS.
COME ON. WHAT? EMBARRASSED?
EVERYBODY IN HERE
IS EMBARRASSED.
NOBODY IN HERE GOT
AWAY WITH ANYTHING.
WHAT'D YOU DO?
LOOK, MAN, I STOLE
A TV, ALL RIGHT?
SO YOU STOLE A TV.
WHAT'S EMBARRASSING ABOUT THAT?
I STOLE A TV FROM A STORE
THAT WAS RIGHT NEXT
DOOR TO A DOUGHNUT SHOP.
I RAN OUT,
THE STORE OWNER'S
BEHIND ME YELLING.
BAM! I RUN INTO 3
COPS, ALL RIGHT?
OH, SEE? SEE, I TOLD YOU
IT WAS EMBARRASSING.
YOU'RE LAUGHING.
WAIT A SEC, WAIT A SEC.
THAT DON'T MAKE SENSE.
NAH, YOU DIDN'T GET 6
YEARS FOR STEALING A TV, MAN.
COME ON.
I GO IN THE STORE, I COME OUT,
THE POLICE OFFICER GRABS MY ARM,
THE TV FALLS ON HIS
FOOT AND BREAKS IT.
THEY SAID I THREW
THE TV AT THE OFFICER.
ASSAULT. 6 YEARS.
COME ON. TELL THE TRUTH.
YOU CHUCKED IT AT HIM...
SOMETHING.
LIKE I SAID,
I CAME OUT OF THE STORE,
HE GRABBED MY ARM,
IT FELL ON HIS FOOT.
COME ON NOW.
WHAT YOU GOT FOR ME?
WHAT YOU GOT FOR ME, HUH?
THERE YOU GO, BABY!
YEAH! THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
BAM!
FUCK YOU!
GIVE ME A TOWEL. HOLD HIM.
YOU WANNA BE A
NIGGER, SWEET BOY?
FUCK YOU!
WE GONNA TREAT YOU LIKE ONE.
NO.
COME ON.
AAH!
Convict: COME
ON, GIVE IT TO HIM!
FUCK YOU!
AHH.
THAT WAS REAL SWEET.
FUCK YOU!
HOW IS HE?
WELL, HE TOOK 6 STITCHES.
MAN, WHAT THE HELL ARE
YOU DOING HERE, ANYWAY?
WELL, I CAME TO
TALK ABOUT DANNY,
BUT WE DON'T HAVE
TO DO THAT RIGHT NOW.
I BROUGHT YOU SOME BOOKS.
WELL, WHAT ABOUT HIM, YOU KNOW?
DON'T KEEP ME IN SUSPENSE.
HE'S HEADED RIGHT WHERE YOU ARE.
OH, MAN. YOU KNOW WHAT?
MY MOTHER ALREADY
LAID THIS TRIP ON ME, MAN.
I'M... DANNY'S NOT
MY RESPONSIBILITY.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT
ME TO DO WITH THAT?
IT DOESN'T HELP ME.
AM I SUPPOSED TO FEEL GUILTY?
I DON'T WANT YOU TO DO ANYTHING.
I NEED TO KNOW THE
TRUTH ABOUT HOW YOU FEEL.
WELL, WHAT YOU THINK
I WANT HIM IN HERE?
I MEAN...
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I FEEL.
I'M ALL...
I FEEL A LITTLE INSIDE OUT.
I'M, YOU KNOW... I DON'T KNOW.
THERE'S SOME THINGS THAT...
THAT DON'T FIT.
WELL, THAT HAPPENS.
LOOK, DEREK, YOU
ARE TOO DAMN SMART
TO BE FLOATING AROUND HERE
PRETENDING YOU DON'T SEE
ALL THE HOLES IN THIS BULLSHIT.
HEY, LISTEN. I SAID
I WAS CONFUSED.
I DIDN'T SAY I
DIDN'T BELIEVE IN I.
ALL RIGHT. THAT'S WHY
YOU HAVE TO STAY OPEN.
RIGHT NOW, YOUR ANGER
IS CONSUMING YOU HERE.
YOUR ANGER IS SHUTTING
DOWN THE BRAIN GOD GAVE YOU.
GOD. YOU KNOW WHAT, MAN?
YOU'VE BEEN TALKING ABOUT
WHAT'S GOING ON WITH ME
SINCE I WAS IN HIGH SCHOOL.
HOW THE FUCK DO YOU KNOW
WHAT'S GOING ON INSIDE ME?
NO, I KNOW ABOUT ME.
I KNOW ABOUT THIS PLACE.
I KNOW ABOUT THE
PLACE YOU ARE IN.
HMMPH.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT THE PLACE I'M IN?
THERE WAS A MOMENT...
WHEN I USED TO BLAME
EVERYTHING AND EVERYONE
FOR ALL THE PAIN AND SUFFERING
AND VILE THINGS
THAT HAPPENED TO ME,
THAT I SAW HAPPEN TO MY PEOPLE.
USED TO BLAME EVERYBODY.
BLAMED WHITE PEOPLE,
BLAMED SOCIETY,
BLAMED GOD.
I DIDN'T GET NO ANSWERS
'CAUSE I WAS ASKING
THE WRONG QUESTIONS.
YOU HAVE TO ASK
THE RIGHT QUESTION.
LIKE WHAT?
HAS ANYTHING YOU'VE DONE
MADE YOUR LIFE BETTER?
NO.
YOU GOTTA HELP ME, MAN.
JUST HELP ME.
GET ME OUT OF HERE, YOU KNOW?
I'M UP IN 4 MONTHS FOR REVIEW.
PUT IN... PUT IN A WORD FOR ME.
I ALREADY HAVE.
SO YOU'RE OUT
THERE, AND THEN WHAT?
I DON'T WANT TO FUCK
UP MY FAMILY ANYMORE.
I'LL GO AS FAR
AWAY AS I CAN GET.
THAT'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH.
YOU WANT MY HELP,
YOU GOTTA DO BETTER THAN THAT.
MY HELP IS NOT UNCONDITIONAL.
RUNNING JUST AIN'T GOOD ENOUGH.
FUCK HIM.
FUCK HIM. LET THE
NIGGERS HAVE HIM.
YO, WHAT'S UP, D?
YO, WHAT'S ALL THAT BULLSHIT
YOU PULLED IN THE MESS HALL?
YOU OUT OF YOUR FUCKIN'
MIND? ARE YOU FUCKIN' CRAZY?
D, LOOK AT ME, MAN!
YOU CAN'T MAKE IT
IN HERE ON YOUR OWN.
LOOK, I'M NOT AFRAID OF
THOSE FUCKIN' PUSSIES, OK?
THERE WAS 6 OF THEM,
AND THEY JUMPED ME.
THAT WON'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
I HOPE THEY FUCKIN' TRY.
LOOK, MAN, I'M NOT TALKING
ABOUT YOUR PECKERWOOD FRIENDS!
THEY'RE PROTECTING
YOUR STUPID ASS!
YOU DISSED THEM IN PUBLIC!
NOW YOU'RE ON YOUR FUCKIN' OWN!
YO, MAN, I'M TALKING ABOUT
THE BROTHERS, ALL RIGHT?
THEY'RE GONNA FUCK
YOU, TORCH YOUR CELL,
THEN SMOKE YOUR
MOTHERFUCKING ASS!
OH, WHY DON'T YOU TELL
ME SOMETHING I DON'T KNOW?
YOU THINK I HAVEN'T
THOUGHT ABOUT THAT?
IF THEY COME FOR ME, THEY COME.
THERE AIN'T NOTHING I CAN DO.
WHAT CAN I DO, MAN?
Derek: SO I WAS RIGHT
BACK WHERE I STARTED.
EVERY DAY I WAS
SURE IT WAS MY DAY.
EVERY TIME I STEPPED
OUT OF MY CELL,
EVERY TIME I GOT IN THAT SHOWER,
I FIGURED IT WAS
ONLY A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE THEY MADE A MOVE.
I JUST HOPED IT'D BE QUICK.
BUT IT NEVER CAME.
I COULDN'T FIGURE IT OUT,
'CAUSE I KNEW SOME OF
THEM WERE ITCHING FOR IT.
AFTER AWHILE, JUST
PUT MY HEAD DOWN
AND READ THE STUFF
THAT SWEENEY SENT ME,
AND I KEPT TO MYSELF.
LAST 6 MONTHS IN THAT PLACE
I WAS LIKE A GHOST.
WHAT'S UP, MAN? YOU GETTING OUT?
COME ON, MAN.
WHAT THE FUCK YOU WAITING ON?
GET THE FUCK ON
OUT OF HERE, MAN.
YEAH, YOU KNOW, I GOT
THIS FUNNY FEELING.
OH, YEAH? WHAT'S THAT?
I'M THINKING MAYBE
THE ONLY REASON
I'M GETTING OUT OF
HEE IN ONE PIECE IS YOU.
COME ON, MAN! GET
THE FUCK OUTTA HERE!
YOU THINK I'M GONNA
PUT MY NECK ON THE LINE
FOR SOME CRAZY ASS PECKERWOOD?
YEAH. RIGHT.
STUPID.
THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT.
I OWE YOU, MAN.
MAN, YOU DON'T OWE
ME SHIT, ALL RIGHT?
YES, I DO.
YOU'LL BE OUTTA HERE IN NO TIME.
MAN, IT'S A PIECE
OF CAKE, ALL RIGHT?
JUST TAKE IT EASY ON
THE BROTHERS, ALL RIGHT?
THE BROTHERS!
GOD, MAN.
SORRY, DEREK.
SORRY THAT HAPPENED TO YOU.
WELL, I'M NOT.
I'M LUCKY.
I FEEL LUCKY, 'CAUSE
IT'S WRONG, DAN.
IT'S WRONG, AND IT
WAS EATING ME UP.
IT WAS GONNA KILL ME.
AND I KEPT ASKING
MYSELF ALL THE TIME,
HOW... HOW DID I
BUY INTO THIS SHIT,
YOU KNOW?
IT'S JUST 'CAUSE
I WAS PISSED OFF.
NOTHING I EVER DID...
EVER TOOK THAT FEELING AWAY.
I MEAN, I KILLED 2 GUYS,
DANNY. I KILLED THEM.
AND IT DIDN'T MAKE
ME FEEL ANY DIFFERENT.
JUST GOT ME MORE LOST,
AND I'M TIRED OF FEELING
PISSED OFF, DANNY.
I'M JUST TIRED OF IT.
AND I'M NOT TELLING
YOU WHAT TO DO.
I'M REALLY NOT.
BUT I NEED YOU TO UNDERSTAND...
'CAUSE I LOVE YOU,
AND YOU'RE MY BEST FRIEND.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
YEAH, I UNDERSTAND.
ALL RIGHT.
WHEW.
JESUS.
HEY.
HI. EVERYTHING OK?
AH, EVERYTHING'S GREAT.
GREAT. YEAH.
YOU WANNA SLEEP IN OUR ROOM?
NO. THANK YOU.
YOU SURE?
YEAH. THIS IS GOOD.
THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT. COME ON, LET'S GO.
GOOD NIGHT.
I'M GONNA TAKE A
SHOWER, ALL RIGHT?
Danny: IT'S HARD TO LOOK BACK
AND SEE THE TRUTH
ABOUT PEOPLE YOU LOVE.
I THINK IF YOU ASKED DEREK
WHY IT ALL WENT THE WAY IT DID
AND WHERE IT ALL STARTED,
HE'S STILL SAY IT STARTED WHEN
OUR FATHER WAS MURDERED.
Danny: THE TRUTH IS,
IT STARTED EARLIER.
ALL RIGHT.
ARE WE ALL MEETING
FOR THE GAME TONIGHT?
YES. DEFINITELY.
ALL RIGHT, BEN'S BURGER AT 7:00,
THEN WE GO WATCH
THE BIG GUY PLAY.
Mom: OK. YEAH.
PSYCHING UP FOR THE GAME?
YEAH, I'M ALWAYS READY FOR THAT.
I... I GOT AN ENGLISH
EXAM THIRD PERIOD.
I'M HAVING A HEART ATTACK.
I'M NOT READY.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
AFRAID YOU'LL GET A "B?"
HA HA. MIGHT DO YOU GOOD.
"B" MINUS.
HEY, DON'T LAUGH.
I'M TELLING YOU, THIS
GUY IS DIFFERENT.
DR. SWEENEY. THIS
GUY'S UNBELIEVABLE.
UNBELIEVABLE. I'VE NEVER
HAD A TEACHER LIKE THIS.
HE'S GOT, LIKE, 2 Ph.D.s.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HE'S
DOING TEACHING AT OUR SCHOOL.
HE'S NOT LIKE OTHER TEACHERS.
WHAT'S HE GOT YOU READING?
WE GOT THIS ESSAY EXAM
ON THIS BOOK NATIVE SON.
ALL ON THIS ONE BOOK.
NATIVE SON? WHAT'S
THAT? I DON'T KNOW THAT.
THAT'S A BIG SURPRISE.
WHAT? I READ.
HONEY, THEY DON'T TEACH
TOM CLANCY IN SCHOOL.
Doris: WELL, THEY DON'T.
SO WHAT IS THIS NATIVE SON?
WHAT IS IT?
IT'S THIS BOOK ABOUT
THIS BLACK GUY, YOU KNOW?
WE'RE DOING THIS WHOLE
BLACK LITERATURE, YOU KNOW?
WHAT, IS IT BLACK HISTORY MONTH?
NO, IT'S JUST, LIKE, THIS
GUY SWEENEY, YOU KNOW?
HE... IT'S PART OF
THE COURSE NOW.
YEAH.
WHAT?
NOTHING. IT'S JUST, YOU KNOW...
IT'S EVERYWHERE I LOOK NOW.
WHAT?
THIS AFFIRMATIVE BLACKTION.
HONEY, A FEW NEW BOOKS
DOESN'T QUALIFY AS
AFFIRMATIVE BLACK ACTION.
HEY, READ THE BOOK,
ACE THE GUY'S TEST.
JUST DON'T SWALLOW
EVERYTHING HE FEEDS YOU WHOLE.
JUST 'CAUSE YOU SEE IT
ON THE EVENING NEWS...
I KNOW, BUT WHAT?
ALL THIS STUFF ABOUT
MAKING EVERYTHING EQUAL.
IT'S NOT THAT SIMPLE.
NOW YOU GOT THIS
BOOK NATIVE SON.
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE
OTHER BOOKS IN THE COURSE?
THEY'RE NOT ANY GOOD ANYMORE
'CAUSE MR. 2 Ph.D. SAYS SO?
HUH?
NOW YOU GOTTA TRADE IN
GREAT BOOKS FOR BLACK BOOKS?
DOES THAT MAKE SENSE?
HUH?
YOU GOTTA QUESTION
THESE THINGS, DEREK.
YOU GOTTA LOOK AT
THE WHOLE PICTURE.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT BOOKS HERE,
BUT I'M ALSO TALKING
ABOUT MY JOB.
I GOT 2 BLACK GUYS
ON MY SQUAD NOW
WHO GOT THEIR JOB OVER
A COUPLE OF WHITE GUYS
WHO ACTUALLY SCORED
HIGHER ON THE TEST.
DOES THAT MAKE SENSE?
HUH?
YEAH, SURE,
EVERYTHING'S EQUAL NOW,
BUT I GOT 2 GUYS
WATCHING MY BACK,
RESPONSIBLE FOR MY LIFE,
WHO AREN'T AS GOOD
AS 2 OTHER GUYS.
THEY ONLY GOT THE JOB
BECAUSE THEY WERE BLACK,
NOT BECAUSE THEY WERE THE BEST.
THAT... THAT SUCKS.
YEAH. IS THAT WHAT
AMERICA'S ABOUT?
NO, AMERICA'S ABOUT
BEST MAN FOR THE JOB.
YOU DO YOUR BEST,
YOU GET THE JOB.
THIS AFFIRMATIVE-ACTION CRAP...
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THAT'S ABOUT.
THERE'S LIKE SOME HIDDEN
AGENDA OR SOMETHING GOING ON.
YOU SEE WHAT I'M SAYING?
YEAH, I DO.
I DON'T KNOW. I DIDN'T
THINK ABOUT IT LIKE THAT.
WELL...
THIS GUY, THOUGH...
I DON'T KNOW.
DR. SWEENEY, HE COMES
ON, LIKE, SO STRONG.
IT'S KINDA HARD NOT
TO LISTEN TO HIM,
BUT MAYBE SOME OF
WHAT HE SAYS IS KINDA...
IT'S BULLSHIT.
YEAH.
YEAH, MAYBE.
NO, NO.
IT'S NIGGER BULLSHIT.
YOU SEE THAT, DON'T YOU?
YEAH.
YOU GOTTA WATCH OUT FOR THAT.
YEAH. NO, I GET
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
I WILL.
GOOD BOY.
I'M PROUD OF YOU.
YEAH. DON'T WORRY
ABOUT IT. I GOT IT.
Danny: AND IN ABOUT MINUTE,
I'M GONNA WATCH THE SUN COME UP.
I DON'T KNOW IF
I'VE EVER DONE THAT.
ANYWAY, WE'RE GONNA
TRY TO PICK THINGS UP
AND START OVER.
IT WON'T BE EASY,
BUT WE'RE ALL TOGETHER AGAIN,
AND I FEEL GOOD.
I'M NOT SURE IF THIS PAPER
IS WHAT YOU WANTED...
IF I HIT THE SOCIAL SIGNIFICANCE
OR WHATEVER YOU'RE LOOKING FOR,
BUT FOR WHAT IT'S WORTH,
THANKS A LOT.
WOW.
YOU LOOK GREAT.
LOOK AT YOU.
YEAH...
GOTTA DRESS UP FOR
THE PAROLE OFFICER.
IS SHE CUTE?
SHE IS A FAT GUY NAMED HECTOR...
OHH. WELL...
SO I'M OUT OF LUCK.
WELL, I JUST GOTTA CHECK IN,
THEN I'M GONNA SEE ABOUT
GETTING MY OLD JOB BACK.
GREAT.
GOOD MORNING.
HEY.
DAVINA, CAN YOU HELP?
YOUR SISTER'S GONNA HELP YOU.
YOU LOOK GREAT. KNOCK 'EM DEAD.
THANKS.
COME ON, SWEETIE.
WHAT WOULD YOU
LIKE TO WEAR TODAY?
Ally: MY OUTFIT FROM YESTERDAY.
YOU DO LOOK GOOD.
YEAH? I FEEL SILLY.
YOU LOOK GOOD.
YEAH?
YOU FEEL GOOD?
YEAH, YEAH.
I... I FEEL, YOU KNOW...
A LITTLE...
I'M... I'M GETTING THERE.
I'M GETTING THERE.
LISTEN...
I DON'T KNOW...
I DON'T KNOW THAT
IT'S OK THAT I'M HERE.
I WANT TO BE HERE.
I'M GONNA GET A PAPER.
COOL.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
A MAPLE BAR AND A LARGE MILK.
ALL RIGHT. I GOT IT.
UH, LET ME GET A COFFEE,
A MAPLE BAR, AND
A LARGE MILK TO GO.
Clerk: RIGHT AWAY.
HEY, DEREK.
HEY.
DEREK, WE NEED TO TALK.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
CAMERON ALEXANDER AND SETH RYAN
ARE AT THE I.C.U. AT ST. JOHN'S.
THEY WERE JUMPED LAST
NIGHT NEAR BEN'S BURGERS.
HOW BAD?
WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE
THEY'RE GONNA LIVE.
THEN THEY GOT LUCKY.
SOMEBODY'S GOTTA LOSE, THOUGH.
OH, WHAT?
WE WERE KINDA HOPING MAYBE
YOU'D TALK TO YOUR OLD CREW...
OH, COME ON. COME ON. NO WAY.
IF THERE'S ANYBODY
THEY'RE GONNA LISTEN TO,
IT'S YOU.
NO. I HATE TO TELL
YOU, BUT I'M OUT, OK?
THOSE GUYS ARE PROBABLY
GUNNING FOR ME NOW.
LOOK, WE'RE ASKING FOR
YOUR HELP HERE, DEREK.
WHAT, DID YOU TELL HIM
I WAS GONNA DO THIS?
DEREK.
THIS HAS GOT NOTHING
TO DO WITH ME ANYMORE.
YES, IT DOES.
IT HAS EVERYTHING
TO DO WITH YOU.
GOD, WHAT ARE YOU DOING TO ME?
I'M DOING MY BEST!
I'M GOING LIKE THIS
JUST TO KEEP MY
FAMILY IN THE CLEAR.
DON'T ASK ME TO FIX
THIS FUCKIN' SITUATION!
I'M NOT ASKING THAT.
IT WAS THERE BEFORE ME.
YOU HELPED CREATE IT.
YOU WANNA TAKE A BREAK NOW?
YOU TAKE A BREAK,
YOU'LL FIND NO PEACE.
THE WAY TO FIND
PEACE IS TO STICK.
IT'S NOT GONNA MAKE A
FUCKIN' BIT OF DIFFERENCE.
IT MIGHT.
NOT A BIT.
I MEAN, DO YOU KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE ASKING ME TO DO?
DO YOU REALLY KNOW?
YES. I'M ASKING YOU
TO DO WHATEVER'S
IN YOUR POWER TO DO.
OHH, MAN.
FUCK.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'RE GONNA DO?
YOU'RE GONNA GET ME SHOT
BY A BUNCH OF WHITE BOYS.
I DOUBT IT.
YEAH.
WE'RE ALL GONNA
HAVE A LAUGH AT THAT,
LET ME TELL YA.
I'M GONNA TAKE HIM TO SCHOOL.
I'LL BE BACK IN A HALF AN HOUR.
COME ON.
Sweeney: HEY, YOU...
YOU GOT SOMETHING
GOOD FOR ME THIS MORNING?
I'LL GIVE IT TO
YOU, DR. SWEENEY.
YEAH, OK.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S COOL?
UH-HUH.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
IT'S JUST SO BAD FOR SETH, MAN.
I WONDER HOW BAD
THEY GOT FUCKED UP.
WELL, I'M GLAD THEY'RE NOT DEAD,
BUT OTHER THAN
THAT, I DON'T CARE.
SHOULD WE VISIT HIM?
VISIT HIM? NO.
NO, DEFINITELY NOT.
DEFINITELY NOT.
JUST STAY OUT OF IT.
LISTEN, TOO...
I SAW A CAR CRUISING
BY THE HOUSE LAST NIGHT
WHEN I PULLED OUT
OF THERE WITH SETH.
IF YOU GET HOME BEFORE ME TODAY,
JUST GIVE A LOOK AROUND
THE STREET, ALL RIGHT?
MAKE SURE THERE'S
NOTHING GOING ON.
HMMPH.
OH, MAN, THIS IS BAD.
THEY'RE AFTER YOU, MAN.
IT'LL COOL OFF.
IF I MADE IT THROUGH
CHINO, YOU KNOW,
THIS SHOULD BE A
PIECE OF CAKE, RIGHT?
YEAH.
YOU GONNA BE OK?
YEAH, YEAH.
OK.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
I DON'T KNOW. I'LL WORK IT OUT.
HEY, KEEP YOUR
HEAD UP, ALL RIGHT?
THINGS ARE GONNA BE FINE.
IT'S GONNA BE FINE.
GO TURN THAT PAPER IN.
OK. ALL RIGHT. SEE YA.
HEY. HEY, DAN.
COME HERE.
I'LL SEE YOU AT HOME.
ALL RIGHT?
YEAH, I'LL SEE YOU.
HEY, GOOD LUCK, ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
SEE YOU LATER.
LIZZY.
GONNA BE LATE.
YEAH, WE BETTER GO.
OK.
ALL RIGHT. COME ON.
BYE.
I'LL CATCH UP WITH
YOU, ALL RIGHT?
SEE YOU LATER.
DEREK, NO!
GET OUT OF MY WAY!
ALL RIGHT! LET HIM GO!
OH, NO.
NO! NO!
NO!
AW, JESUS.
NO.
OHH, NO.
NO!
NO.
OH, JESUS.
GOD, WHAT DID I DO?
OHH, GOD.
OH, MY GOD.
Danny: SO I GUESS
THIS IS WHERE I TELL
YOU WHAT I LEARNED.
MY CONCLUSION, RIGHT?
WELL, MY CONCLUSION IS...
HATE IS BAGGAGE.
LIFE'S TOO SHORT TO BE
PISSED OFF ALL THE TIME.
IT'S JUST NOT WORTH IT.
DEREK SAYS IT'S ALWAYS GOOD
TO END A PAPER WITH A QUOTE.
HE SAYS SOMEONE ELSE
HAS ALREADY SAID IT BEST,
SO IF YOU CAN'T TOP IT,
STEAL FROM THEM
AND GO OUT STRONG.
SO I PICKED A GUY I
THOUGHT YOU'D LIKE.
"WE ARE NOT ENEMIES,
"BUT FRIENDS.
"WE MUST NOT BE ENEMIES.
"THOUGH PASSION
MAY HAVE STRAINED,
"WE MUST NOT BREAK
OUR BONDS OF AFFECTION.
"THE MYSTIC CHORDS OF MEMORY
"WILL SWELL WHEN AGAIN TOUCHED,
"AS SURELY THEY WILL BE
BY THE BETTER ANGELS
OF OUR NATURE."
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE
BY NEW LINE HOME VIDEO
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE, INC.
PUBLIC PERFORMANCE OF
CAPTIONS PROHIBITED WITHOUT
PERMISSION OF NATIONAL
CAPTIONING INSTITUTE