Mike! What the hell are you doing?
It's called driving, Marcus.
Slow down.
What? Four minutes?
Speed up.
Oh, so you want me to speed up
and slow down at the same time?
Moving southbound on Collins.
Fast approaching 22 Street.
Copy that.
Air support has a visual.
Mike!
I'm about to throw up.
Oh, you bett... The hell not.
That is hand-stitched leather.
You better drink it.
I'm blocking off 6th Street now.
That was your turn, Mike!
Damn it! Look, you are the navigator, okay?
That's why you're sitting in that seat.
And where are your glasses?
You need to put your glasses on.
- I don't need glasses.
- Marcus, you can't see shit.
Oh, sh... Mike. Mike. Mike.
- Relax. Relax. Relax!
- Mike. Bus, bus, bus.
Sorry, rich white people.
We're not just black, we're cops too.
We'll pull ourselves over later.
Hey, even the Batmobile don't hold
the road like this bitch.
Get me the fuck out of this car.
- Hey!
- Oh, shit.
Come on, man.
- You can get that buffed out.
- No. You can get that buffed out.
- Miami PD. Make a hole.
- Coming through.
- Make a hole. Miami PD.
- Miami PD.
Go! Go!
Sorry.
Daddy!
Joker.
You a pop-pop.
- Baby, look at him.
- Yeah.
No doubt. It's in the eyes.
And the ears.
And the name.
Marcus Miles Burnett.
But that's my name.
His name too. We decided to name him
after you. It was Reggie's idea.
Thought it would be a very respectful
gesture, sir. I hope you approve.
That's cool.
But you know you still need to make
a honest woman out of my baby girl there.
Uncle Mike,
ready to hold the baby?
No. Uncle Mike don't want to
catch that.
Okay? That's that shit.
- No, Mike.
- Stop.
- Look at the baby.
- Stop it right now. Seriously.
Look at the baby.
Okay, you know what? I'll be outside
when you get your shit together.
Mike.
- The baby.
- Oh, it's okay.
Let's go, ladies.
You're useless.
Move it!
Aretas.
What the fuck?
Stop the ambulance!
Mama.
My son.
Don't be sad for his death.
The spirit of your father is free
from the bars that confined him.
This is the last gift
from Papa before he died.
You're a man now. You're finally ready
for what needs to be done.
You must bring honor
and respect back to our family.
Your father hid millions
of dollars before he was locked up.
Here are the coordinates
where you can find them.
We'll take back what's ours.
With this money,
we can finally get revenge.
The people who destroyed our family will know
how it feels to be hunted.
He dies last.
Come here, Marcus.
Come here.
We're here to celebrate
and to raise a glass to one of our own.
And I sincerely hope that someday
your namesake follows in the footsteps
of his old-ass grandpa
to protect and serve our fair city.
To Marcus.
- To Marcus!
May the name Marcus Burnett strike fear into the hearts
and minds of assholes for years to come.
Thank y'all.
Thank... Thank you all.
Mike and I, we're going on 25 years
of working these streets.
And I like to think
we made a difference.
You all are the best.
And I thank you.
It's been a real honor.
Marcus!
Marcus! Marcus! Marcus!
Daddy buried that cash deep, huh?
If these are empty,
you're still gonna owe.
Buried treasure in the ocean.
I heard the stories
pero coño...
Should cover the cost of
the materials we discussed.
And then some.
This is what you get to keep.
What'd you say?
We had a deal.
I'm renegotiating.
Come here.
Look at me.
I don't renegotiate.
My family's taking back
management of this town.
We're gonna need some loyal employees.
Who wants a job?
So how's your dental?
Say that again.
Stay calm.
You give yourselves a raise.
You start with that pile right there.
Okay?
Okay.
You work for me now.
Get your people to fall in line, stay out
of my fucking way, and I won't kill you.
Get this money.
Mama.
Armando.
It's ours.
That was fast.
We got a new base of
operations too.
You've spent so much time on the other side,
you sound like a gringo.
I'm done, Mike.
Oh, here we go again.
No, this time it's different.
When I looked into that little baby's eyes,
something changed.
I want to spend my days
watching that little boy grow.
Theresa does not want your ass sitting
at home, getting fat and breaking shit.
Mike, we got more time
behind us than in front.
It's time to make some changes,
for real.
You can miss me with that.
I'm living my best life.
You're dyeing your goatee, Mike.
- What?
- You're dyeing your goatee.
I am not dyeing my goatee.
That's Midnight Cocoa Bean.
I recognize that shit.
- Go ahead with that shit.
- That ain't Midnight Cocoa...?
- Go ahead somewhere.
- Let me ask you something.
You want your legacy to be
muscle shirts and a body count?
Don't you know family is
all that matters?
Hey, granddaddy!
- Rita.
- Oh, no. Pop-pop.
He's going with Pop-pop.
- Pop-pop?
- Yeah.
Got pics, Pop-pop?
- Oh, you know I do, right? There you go.
- Let's see.
Oh, my God, the ears!
Yeah, my grandbaby.
That's my grandbaby.
I love him.
Yeah. And congrats to you,
lieutenant.
I hear Howard tapped you
to head up AMMO.
Congrats.
What's AMMO?
Advanced Miami Metro Operations.
A small team trained in new tactics
and investigative methods.
Gonna replace us old dogs.
Or teach them some new tricks.
For real, Marcus.
So happy for you.
Thank you.
Hey, guys!
Hey! Everyone's here.
How are you?
Dumbass.
- What?
- She is perfect for you.
Smart as hell.
Confident. Ambitious.
She just wasn't the one for me.
- All right?
- What is for you?
Dying all alone and sad as shit?
You just jealous.
- How long you been married? Twenty years?
- Twenty-six.
Tell the truth.
When's the last time you had sex?
- That ain't none of your damn business.
- Exactly.
How many great women
are you gonna let go?
You get a lot of loving,
but have you ever really been in love?
Of course. I mean, yeah,
I was... I was in love.
One time.
A long, long time ago.
You never told me.
Nigga, I don't tell you
all my business.
Look, all you need to know is that
I'll be running down criminals till I'm 100.
You the last brother that needs to be talking
about running down anyone after the hospital.
The hospital? What you talking about?
What happened at the hospital?
Running to see baby Marcus.
I dusted your ass.
You spent that run staring
at my one good ass-cheek, Mike.
You're saying that you actually outran me?
You beat me in a footrace?
It's been said.
Oh, hell, no.
Nothing sadder than old men
revisiting the past.
Hey, no stretching.
Stretching is cheating.
Hey, who you got, Cap?
I got 50 on a torn ACL.
I ain't running for free.
What's the bet?
I win, we lay it down.
We turn in our papers and we retire.
All right, when I win, you stop all this
foolish retirement talk.
We ride this thing till
the wheels fall off. Bad boys for life.
Bad boys ain't really boys anymore.
Hey, Cap, just have the ambo on standby.
Old boy gonna need fluids and oxygen.
- That's him, Cap. That's him.
- Okay.
On your mark, get set, go!
- Go, Marcus! You got this!
- Where you at?
- You got this, baby! Breathe!
Come on, baby!
Breathe, baby, breathe!
Go!
Where you at, baby?!
Mike!
- Mike. Mike! Oh, shit! Get some help!
- Captain Howard.
I got an officer down.
We're on Ocean Drive, 700 block.
- Hold on.
- Gunshot wound.
- Oh, shit.
- What happened?
- Just get... Get some help!
- Who did this?!
- Who the fuck did this?!
- The shooter's driving a black motorcycle...
Come on. Don't do this.
Don't do this.
- Mike, stay with us.
- Come on.
Get an ambulance!
- Come on, Mike. Come on.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Phone... I got him on the phone.
You gonna be all right. You gonna make it through this.
Come on, man. Stay with us, man.
Come on, Mike. I'm right here.
Dear God...
it's me, Marcus.
You blessed me
with a lot of stuff lately.
I know I haven't been
to church in a while.
Probably Easter.
But I ain't gonna lie,
I wasn't paying attention.
I haven't lost faith.
It's just...
I was ashamed at some of
the stuff we had to do.
I know "thou shall not kill,"
but they were bad guys,
all of them.
You know, Mike hardly had
a life yet.
No wife, no kids.
If you could just please find
it in your heart
to give him one more chance, man.
Straight up,
he's my best friend.
My brother.
If you just spare him,
I swear to you,
I will put no more violence
in this world.
A drive-by shooting has a famed Miami Dade
police officer fighting for his life.
Witnesses report hearing shots
and a blacked-out bike fleeing the scene.
Detective Mike Lowrey remains
in critical condition.
Let's run Cap through what we got on the case.
Kelly, run us through ballistics.
So the slugs in Officer Lowrey
were SS190.
P90 fires that caliber,
the Herstal.
But these were subsonic 5.7-by-28s,
custom rounds.
I wanna know who made those bullets.
We are watching 4chan and cross-referencing
the players in the market with the feds' red lines.
Mike's like a son to me.
I want this asshole.
This is personal for me too.
- Let's bring every single thing we got, all right?
- You got it.
I made it clear,
Lowrey dies last.
I'm the one up here.
I've learned how to handle things,
all right?
You've had me
training my whole life.
The cop was a threat.
The others are nothing!
Do you listen to me or not?
I wanted him to see the others die.
Just finish it.
Never disobey me again!
Retired DA Rodrigo Vargas was
gunned down this afternoon.
The DEA is mourning Dr. Jack Weber this evening,
a 20-year forensic investigator for the agency in Miami.
There you are.
In yet another
execution-style homicide,
Judge Leon Sorenson was shot outside
his courthouse late Wednesday.
The war on law enforcement continues.
Three other law enforcement personnel
have been killed that could be linked to our case.
- It's a war on the goddamn law.
- All the same shooter as Mike.
- Connected how?
- Traffic cams, witnesses, tire treads,
all put the same blacked-out bike
at the scene.
We want to thank you all
for joining us today.
It means a lot to the family.
And I now pronounce you man and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
I really gotta stop crying
like this.
Hey, you guys are great.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's time for our first toast.
I'm going to bring up
Officer Mike Lowrey,
affectionately known as Uncle Mike.
All right. Let's do this.
First off, Reggie,
I am shocked that you are even still here.
I remember your first date with Megan,
and trust me, me and Marcus did everything
we could possibly do to make sure you never came back.
But I'm telling you,
love is hard.
And your relationship
will be tested.
And your father and I have weathered
storm after storm.
And we have a mantra that
we say to each other
in our darkest days,
and it always seems
to bring us back together.
And, Reggie, Megan,
I would like to share it with you.
We ride together,
- we die together.
- We die together.
Bad boys for life!
No.
- No, what?
- You know what.
From the minute I heard you were still breathing,
I've been waiting for the shit to hit the fan.
Look at me, Mike. No.
- You don't even know what I'm gonna say.
- I know you. I know what you're gonna say.
AMMO's got this.
AMMO?
Come on, Cap.
With all due respect,
AMMO is a high school musical...
boy band with guns.
They don't even have shit.
How do you know what they have
or don't have? They have!
- What do they have? What?
- They have.
The bullets they carved out of you,
they were custom rounds for the P90 Herstal.
AMMO's gonna find the dealer
- that supplied your shooter.
- How?
- State-of-the-art police work, that's how.
- Cap, look... All right.
- Sir.
- Sir?
You are desperate.
But I can't.
Mike, I can't let you
investigate your own case.
- All right. Let me investigate the Vargas case.
- No.
The last thing I need is having IAD shoving
a Hubble telescope up my ass
for a full-on colonoscopy.
- You know the rules.
- Fuck the rules, Cap.
Come on. Put me and Marcus
on this shit.
Have you talked to your partner?
You retired?
It's my daughter's wedding, Mike.
Do we have to do this right now?
Yeah.
- I told you I was retiring.
- Wha...? What?
Wait, nah, hold up.
We raced, you lost.
Now you reneging? What happened
to bad boys for life?
Yeah, for life. It's off.
You died.
What? What the hell are you
talking about?
You coded out, Mike,
three times.
Marcus, look,
this motherfucker stole something
from me and I need it back.
What did he take
from you, Mike?
You're still here.
All he took from you was the legend,
"Bulletproof Mike."
But I saw you
on the ground bleeding.
You're human, just like
the rest of us.
Yeah, his ass bleeds too.
I'm telling you, Mike.
You go out there for vengeance,
you gonna get someone killed.
Oh, we definitely bringing
some smoke.
That fool put holes in me!
And you're filling them
with hate, Mike.
Look, you need to start thinking
about your karma, man.
This was a sign.
A sign, yeah.
A sign to turn up.
So I'm supposed to bow down now?
Give this bitch a pass?
"Turn up"?
What are you, 20?
You need to turn that shit off.
You know, Mike...
Rita called me every day you were
in the hospital.
There's something still there,
a future.
My future is hunting
this motherfucker.
Well, it's not mine.
All right.
So let me get this straight.
So somebody get to dump my ass out
in the street
and you ain't gonna do shit?
You just gonna quit?
How dare you, man?
I sat by your bedside.
I wiped the drool
off your chin, Mike.
- Don't disrespect me like that because you don't know.
- All right. All right, man.
Look, Marcus,
I'm asking you.
I'm begging you, man.
I need this.
Bad boys...
one last time.
No, Mike.
No.
Everything for you, Papa.
Mama.
He didn't die.
Isn't that what you wanted?
Santa Muerte wouldn't let him die
before he suffered as we have.
Don't kill him
until I tell you.
He will suffer.
A little something
for your fans...
Video of a shooting of
a Miami detective has surfaced online,
going viral in a matter
of hours.
The video first appeared on the darknet
and soon spread to mainstream social media.
Authorities believe the shooter uploaded
the video himself.
Too slow.
You're slipping.
Still had the key.
What's up?
Howard told me you wanted back in.
Obviously, that can't happen.
Says who?
Michael, you got shot.
- Yeah, people keep reminding me of that.
- Well, why do you think that is?
- Oh, you shrinking me now.
- You always say that when you don't wanna get real.
No, I always say that
when you start shrinking me.
Hey, this is the type of case
that AMMO was built for.
- You just have to trust me, that's all.
- Oh, come on. What?
Why you always go there?
This don't have nothing to do
with me trusting you or not.
- Oh, no?
- No.
Are you even healed?
- Yeah, I'm fine. Yeah.
- Yeah?
- You sure you're fine?
- Oh, shit. Rita.
- Rita. Stop.
- Hey. This is me you're trying to bullshit.
- Rita...
If you get involved, you're gonna
make mistakes you can't take back.
What does that mean?
Where'd you get that?
Until you burn?
Until you die?
You know me well enough
to know not to ask me to quit.
It's because I know you,
I'm asking.
Because I care about you.
As a friend.
Let us handle this.
Shit. Alexa, turn down
the volume.
Marcus! You need to get out
of the house!
Sorry, baby.
So sorry.
How about a spa day?
- Is that Manny's car?
- Yeah.
- Where's Manny?
- In the back.
Oh, shit. Mike Lowrey.
What are you doing here, man?
You look like a ghost, man.
You know they say you're dead, fuckboy.
I got to show you something.
The streets is talking.
That cop shit ain't working for you.
Come work for me
at Manny's Prime Rib.
See, look,
you get dropped right here.
And guess what.
You're trending worldwide.
My fucking hand, man!
Yo, this ain't
no fucking cop shit, man!
What happened about reading my rights?
This is not how it's supposed to go.
You're supposed to ask me questions,
and then I tell you, "Go fuck yourself!"
What the fuck, man?
Fuck!
- My fucking hand, man.
- P90 Herstals, custom, who's making them?
Mike, I'm not
in the game no more.
Oh, nah?
Okay. My bad.
- Mike, Mike, fucking chill, man.
- So all these vegans in Miami,
and you want me to believe that that hot rod
you got outside comes from selling pork chops?
I work at Manny's. I'm a family man,
and I'm a hardworking man.
I got you...
Oh, shit. Oh, man.
- Did you just get pig fat on my suit?
- Oh, shit.
Sorry, Mike.
Sorry.
No! Booker Grassie!
That's the name! Booker Grassie!
That's the name, man!
Yo, Mike! Mike! Yo, Mike!
The handcuffs, man!
Booker Grassie.
Only arms dealer in Miami customizing
for the P90 Herstal.
What'd I tell you?
I know. I'm not supposed to investigate
my own case. I know the rules.
But this fool posted a video
of him trying to kill me.
I saw it.
- I can go after him vigilante style, or you can bring me in.
- Or I could shoot you myself.
Fuck me!
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
If...
I bring you in, to consult,
and you go cowboy on me,
I need you to comprehend
the level-five shitstorm I will be drowning in.
No gold-plated watch.
No cop retirement village.
I'm sticking myself out on a skinny limb!
Scratch that.
A twig in an ice storm!
Me, on the edge, "tithering."
You mean, teetering?
That's what I said!
And picture me very fat!
- Think I got the image, Cap.
- What is he doing here?
He's gonna be helping out.
- I don't want him.
- I'm not working with her.
He's not. You're not.
He's consulting. It's your show.
- Captain, come on.
- Wait.
I know you guys got history together,
so let's not make it personal.
- Personal? I'm the only one being a professional here.
- This is not détente. I'm informing you of my decision.
- This is a bad idea.
- He's gonna investigate this case, no matter what!
So this way, we keep him
on a short leash, we control him.
I'm standing right here, Cap.
Mike will consult.
He'll observe.
That's it.
Now, what do you got?
Picked up chatter. The dealer we think customed
those Herstal rounds, he's making another sale.
Booker Grassie.
Did you share any other
confidential information?
What? Not me.
He's the one that told me.
Guess my old tricks still work
a little bit.
You're a distraction.
You see that?
That's what I like, teamwork.
Already a beautiful relationship.
- The video, presumed to be posted by the shooter...
- Guys.
This is Detective Michael Lowrey.
He'll be joining us as an adviser only.
Police have no suspects.
And the shooter is
still at lar...
Nice to meet you all as well.
- Thrilled to see you've had a...
- Sweet.
- I am much better now. Thank you.
- I am so sorry about that.
You look good, Michael.
Look, she calls me by my whole government name,
but everybody... You can just do Mike.
- For sure, Mike.
- Got it, Mike.
Yeah, sure thing, Michael.
Oh, so you're that guy.
- Hey, there's always one.
- Yeah. Right up till there's not.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- It's Mike Lowrey, okay?
- Be cool. For once.
- Let's load up!
Think I might be able to hang out
with you guys after all.
Nah, nah, that ain't the one.
We're taking The Crawdaddy.
Wait until you see the inside.
- You need any help, Gramps?
- Go ahead somewhere, boy.
Look at you trying
to be all cool and shit.
Okay, everybody is way too serious.
Raids are supposed to be fun.
They're like field trips with guns.
This is not a raid.
It's surveillance.
Surveillance? Right.
Meaning we're just gonna watch the crime.
We'll record him in the deal
and bring him in facing serious time.
Then we'll get him to talk and he's gonna
tell us everything that we need to know.
Or since he's gonna be there
and we're gonna be there,
I mean, we could just grab him.
Thank you for your input.
Okay.
Listen up. Booker Grassie is the guy
that sold the bullets we took out of Michael.
Hey, look, you think you could stop
calling me Michael in front of everybody?
It's your name.
Okay.
Relax and clear your mind.
Use God's inspiration to bring
people peace and tranquility
by penetrating their souls
with your heart.
We're here.
Excuse me, Mr. Lowrey.
- Just need to get past you, please. Thanks.
- Sure thing, buddy.
You're the tech, huh?
They just leave you in the van?
Yeah, I'm more comfortable
in here.
Got it.
Sending in Big Barry.
You're not Big Barry?
He's our surveillance drone.
So you send the drone in.
Let's fly.
I guess Barry gets
to have all the fun.
There. Black pickup truck.
That's our H-77 Boyz.
Who are they?
These guys are definitely
from out of town. Trying to step up.
I need wide angle, whole deal.
Zoom in.
Booker's hooking them up
with a crate of 5.7-by-28s.
- That's Booker Grassie.
- There's our deal.
Audio.
Here it is.
These will put a hole through anyone
and anything you point your gun at.
I guarantee my product.
- He's right there, Rita. We can grab him.
- No.
I'm not risking the collateral damage.
- Let's move.
- Let's wait.
- You're the boss.
- Yeah, I know.
- That's what I just said. Okay.
- Yeah, I just confirmed it.
You two used to date, right?
- Sort of.
- Not really.
Need to see the cash.
- See the cash.
- Wait.
- Back. Go back. Right there. That guy.
- What?
- I need to see it.
- The bag is empty.
- There's no money in the bag. It's a rip.
- If you see mine, I need to see yours.
- They're gonna kill... It's a rip.
- Michael.
- We need Booker alive!
- Michael, get back here!
Shit. Kelly, go. Go!
Get me body cams.
Michael, do not engage until we have
the rest of the team in position.
Can we count the cash,
or what?
This is a nice song.
Put it louder.
Now!
Move!
Put it down! Put it down!
Can you hear me?
I'm gonna need you to lay me
down some cover. We're coming to you.
All right. You wanna live, you stay with me.
Fuck with me and I'm gonna kill you.
Coming at you on three.
Bring the truck! Grab the merch!
One, two, three.
Shit.
Shit. Hey. Hey. Booker.
Booker, look at me.
Hey. Hey. Don't die.
P90 Herstals. P90 Herstals,
who's the buyer?
Oh, shit.
- Hey, hey. Booker. Booker.
- Michael?
Hey, get an ambulance in here now.
Get the paramedics.
- Booker. Booker.
- Michael.
- Don't worry about clearance. Bring them in.
- Calm down.
- Hey, just do what I ask you for once, please!
- He's dead!
Is that Diego or his twin?
Yeah, yeah, his twin.
Carmelita, no, no, no.
- Who this?
- Yo, Marcus. It's Carver Remy.
Look here, I'm busy, all right?
Don't waste my time, Carver. Leave me alone.
Come on, man.
It's important.
Keep an eye on my baby.
- Marcus.
- I'm retired.
Only rats I talk to are
in my basement.
- Carmelita shot the wrong twin!
- Oh, shit.
The guy who shot Mike,
he's trying to kill me.
- What?
- I'm serious.
A guy on a black bike's been tracking me.
The one on the news. It's him.
- Bullshit.
- Marcus, would I lie to you?
- Yes. That's why we stopped using your ass as a CI.
- I'm telling you, it's him.
- What do you want from me?
- Protective custody. To not die.
Please, man. Use me as bait,
whatever.
You want this guy?
He's coming for me.
- You talk to Mike?
- I called you. Nineteenth and Miami.
Third floor.
I'll be waiting.
What did I say? No, no.
What did I say?
I said consult.
I said observe. I...
Look at this mess. It's carnage!
I didn't do all this shit, Cap.
They did this to each other.
Wait, wait, wait.
You didn't shoot anybody?
- You know I shot some people, but...
- Yeah.
- Look, they had already started.
- What...? Jesus. Mike, you promised.
- No, no, I didn't promise.
- You promised.
- I said I could picture you on a limb, fat as hell...
- Yeah?
- ...with sharks and some shit.
- Right. That's a promise.
- You were here to watch.
- What? Yeah, and I saw.
All right, Cap, look.
The bag is empty, all right? No cash.
The guy reached up and scratched his nose.
I saw it had no weight to it.
- That's very impressive, sir.
- Yeah. See, I like that one.
If I hadn't come in,
Grassie was a dead man for sure.
That's a relief because your guy's
in a body bag and he sure looks dead.
- Cap.
- Good job, Mikey.
Hey, look.
Young boy, seriously.
Let me tell you something. You need to stay
in a child's place, all right?
Spare me the street knowledge, grandpa.
Nobody asked you.
Look, just because I fucked your mother
don't make me your grandpa, all right?
- That's enough. That's enough. Stop, all right?
- You got me fucked up.
- Old ass.
- Stand down! Let's go.
- You better go on.
- Let's go.
- I will knock your ass clean the fuck out.
- Knock me out. Hit me.
What am I, a nursery school teacher? Come on, let's go!
- Shit. I got time today.
- Cool down. Cool down. Keep walking.
- Excuse me, sir.
- Go ahead, man.
- Do you guys want a...?
- No, go. Just go ahead somewhere.
What?
What, quitter?
This is some sad shit.
- Where the hell is your ride?
- Girls took it to the spa.
You all right?
I'm fine. You all right?
Never felt better.
I mean, you could,
if you wanted to,
just do the speed limit.
You let a Prius pass us.
And what is that? What, you got
your balls tucked up in there?
Hey. You know what? Neither one of my balls
wanna be here with your stupid ass.
You brought Little Marcus
on a murder investigation?
We're dropping him at the spa.
Dropping him off at the spa?
Carver is scared.
He is not gonna wait, man.
It's on the way, Mike.
And what's the person that shot me want
with a snitch like Carver Remy anyway?
I'm taking you to find out,
motherfucker.
Sorry about that, Little Marcus.
Pop-pop shouldn't be
swearing like that.
Only when you're dealing
with people like Mike Lowrey,
you got no fucking choice.
Sorry. There I go again.
- Take the baby in.
- I ain't going in there.
Then you ain't gonna find out
who tried to kill you.
See, if I go in there, I know
who's gonna kill me. Theresa Burnett.
- Stop fucking around. Take your baby. Go ahead in there.
- Mike, Carver's scared.
He ain't gonna wait all day.
All right.
No. Mike! Mike!
Tell Marcus I'm gonna kill him!
Go, go!
- Go, go, go!
- What'd she do? What'd you do?
- Is she coming? She coming? Oh, shit!
- Go, go, go!
Mike, you known Theresa a long time.
How pissed would you say she was?
What you mean?
Like, one to 10?
- Yeah, 10 being...
- Like when I broke up with your sister?
No. That was me at a 10.
- Why would you bring that up?
- All right. I'm just trying to...
No, a Theresa 10 would be...
Me that time you spilled
the Frappuccino in my Ferrari.
- Yeah, yeah, that's it. That's it.
- She's probably like a nine, then.
- A nine? Oh, sh...
- Yeah, man.
Oh, shit.
Better make it a 10.
- Forgot to give her the baby wipes.
- Oh, tragedy.
Are you stopping?
Dude, that was a yellow light.
We are in a hurry.
Come on...
Oh, what? You embarrassed
to be seen like this?
We got Mike Lowrey here!
Mike Lowrey in a Nissan Quest!
Nobody gives a shit, Mike.
He's... He's my Uber driver!
A big part of fighting crime
is being ahead of the criminals.
You don't have to stop for pigeons.
You just drive up to them. They'll fly away.
That better be a safe...
or a piano.
- This is my wife's car!
- And that's fucking Carver Remy!
You don't know that's Carver Remy.
That could be anybody.
- Cover the front door!
- I'm retired!
I'm a civilian!
This is a sign.
It's a sign from God.
Oh, shoot.
She knows.
She always knows.
I need 315 at the Broadmoor Hotel.
Fuck!
God, I know I asked you
to help Mike out before...
but he's really getting
his ass whupped.
Lord, give me a sign.
What the hell are you doing?
Mike!
Shit!
You okay?
I'm better than you gonna be
when Theresa see this car.
I had him.
I had him right there.
I don't understand, Mama.
Armando...
A bullet is mercy for this son of a bitch
who took your father from me.
He needs to suffer.
Then he dies.
You understand?
Yes.
Pass it! Pass it! Thattagirl!
Thattagirl, Callie!
Make them wanna play soccer!
You're done, Mike.
Yeah, I know.
No! If she fouls you,
you foul her back!
- Yes!
- Yeah.
So there's this...
This Buddhist guy, right?
And, you know, mountain man, way up high,
going down this long winding road.
And out of nowhere,
this other guy's riding
a horse right toward him.
He's Buddhist too,
I think.
- Actually, I'm not sure.
- Just let them both be Buddhist, Cap.
Okay, fine.
So the guy on the horse is
riding toward our guy so fast
that our guy's gotta get out of the way,
so as not to be trampled by the horse.
And the guy gets up, all dusty, and he goes,
"Hey, where the fuck are you going?"
And our guy on the horse,
he says:
"I don't know!
Ask the horse!"
Ask the horse?
Exactly.
- Yes!
See that face...? That. That?
That's it.
That was my face.
The horse represents
all of our fears and traumas.
And it's got us running around
a hundred miles an hour,
to the point where we can't
even answer a simple question.
"Where are you going?"
Where are you going, Mike?
No, Callie!
Don't pass!
Shooters shoot!
Kid's got the family curse.
Mike...
you gotta get control of your life.
You gotta grab the reins
before your horse
runs you off a cliff.
Come over for dinner.
Callie would love to see you.
I'll read you a Buddhist story.
I got a book full of them.
- Wait, you gonna be cooking again?
- Hell, yeah.
- All right, all right. We'll order pizza.
- Yeah, I think I can do that.
Bingo.
- Cap!
- I don't know! I don't know! Go, go, go!
Get him.
I can help. What does he need?
Shoot.
- Through the bitch.
- Move.
- Move. Get behind the car.
- No. I can help.
Move! Get behind the car!
What's wrong with you, man?
You had that shot.
No innocents.
You crazy, man, you know that?
Three-fifteen. Shots fired.
Officer down.
Jose Marti Park.
We need Air One on a three.
This is Detective Mike Lowrey.
The captain is down.
Ready! Aim! Fire!
You were right, man.
You said if I went out there,
I was gonna get somebody killed.
One last time?
One last time.
Mama, they're all gone.
It's time?
Yes, kill him.
But before you do it, look in his eyes
and tell him something for me.
What, Mama?
I ran a suspicious financial report on Booker.
All his LLC fronts have the same accountant.
Picante Jenkins, CPA.
Yep. You don't meet
too many Picantes.
- So we just gonna do a knock-and-talk?
- Yeah.
- What the hell is all that?
- What you talking about?
Mike, you don't need
a grenade launcher.
Yeah, but I want one.
He's an accountant, Mike.
- Look, we're not going in there like that.
- Like what?
Hey, look, all our lives,
we've been bad boys, all right?
Now it's time to be good men.
Who in the hell
wanna sing that song?
Good men, good men
What you gonna do?
Well, maybe if you sang the song
like you meant it, it'd catch on.
Nah.
Knock and talk.
Yeah. Knock, knock.
- Mike! Mike! Mike!
- Miami PD! Get down!
- Mike! Mike!
- Get down!
- What is happening?
- Mike! What happened to knock and talk?
- Hey, you broke my door. You broke my door!
- Sir, sorry about the door, okay?
- A little Gorilla Glue will make that just fine.
- Hey, where's your warrant?
I need you on your knees with your hands
behind your head right now!
Sir, if you keep moving,
I'm gonna shoot you in your face.
- No, he's not.
- Yes, I am!
Mike, the man is an accountant.
We just need to talk to him.
So you wanna have a conversation
- with a coked-out orange mountain?
- Here's the latest figures.
Look, let me handle this, okay?
Just back up.
I'm gonna penetrate
this man's soul with my heart.
What?
Yeah.
Watch and learn.
Hey! Hey, ass licker.
I'm gonna fast-food fist-fuck you.
Sir, that's just nasty.
- Now, I recognize that this is a difficult situation.
- Don't come over here.
- Don't go over there.
- We just need your client's receipts.
- What?
- Booker Grassie.
Any record of...?
Hey. How deep you think
you got in his soul?
- Sometime you gotta suffer for what is right.
- Don't you turn that other cheek.
- Get off me!
- All right.
Now, sir, I realize
that you're scared.
Hell, we all scared.
You know, sometimes fear just...
So, what you thinking?
I think you should
handle this one.
Yeah, me too.
Hey!
MLK just tapped out.
You got Brother Malcolm now.
We can handle this
by any means necessary.
Hey, I recognize you.
You're that cop that got shot.
Bad year you're having,
Butterscotch.
If you didn't have that gun
and badge, I'd fucking eat you.
This the only thing that's keeping you
from eating me, huh?
Yeah.
Bring it, big boy.
- Left line clear!
- Cuff him.
What the hell are y'all doing here?
I called them.
What?
What happened to bad boys
one last time?
This is one last time.
But this here's the remix, Mike.
We work with AMMO now.
That's that shit, okay?
You got three seconds
before I bite it off.
Get your damn finger out my face.
So tell us. Judge, prosecutor,
criminal informant, the captain, and you.
- Who do you all have in common?
- Hundreds of investigations, operations...
Eight hundred and forty-seven cases
in the nexus of all the victims.
- Well, who up there wants to kill you?
- Hell, who doesn't?
- All right.
- That just the criminals that we're looking at.
I don't trust a person that don't wanna kill him.
Hell, put my name up there.
- Thanks. We got it. We appreciate it.
- What you get out of the accountant?
- His records are a mess.
- Surprising.
But I did manage to get
into his Keychain.
- So?
- All of his social.
Boom.
A lot of dick pics
but not so many clues.
- Facial rec for anyone in our system.
- On it.
It's three days
before I got hit.
Hey, go back to that last shot.
The chain.
Yeah, zoom in.
- Zway Lo.
Who's Zway Lo?
Lorenzo Rodriguez.
Goes by Zway Lo.
Used to coach him in peewee hoops
before he went for that thug shit.
Great player, but I had to bench him
during the championship.
You benched a 10-year-old
in the championship game?
Yeah. Little fucker called me
a dickhead.
- Did y'all win at least?
- Hell, no.
He was our star player.
We lost by 40, but I made my point.
Okay, there's no "I" in "team."
- There is one in "dickhead" though.
- Man, shut up.
Look, Zway Lo's into drugs,
weapons.
He's one of Taglin's lieutenants.
Taglin was found dead
the same night Mike got shot.
I guess he's someone else's
lieutenant now.
Lorenzo Rodriguez.
No mortgage,
not even a bank account.
But it is his birthday tomorrow.
If he's celebrating,
there's three spots for a cat like that.
Ditto, Ice 45, Zillion.
Can you get into their club records?
Ice 45 should up their cyber security.
Okay. Ice 45.
Ditto. Zillion.
There. Rodriguez.
- Bam.
- The party's tonight.
Zillion it is.
All right, we meet at the club at 2300, UC,
so wear your Sunday best.
This is a grab. We're in. We're out.
No bodies. This raid is strictly nonlethal.
Nonlethal.
Has anyone informed the bad guys?
ACLU rounds.
Rubber.
Trust me, you'll enjoy them.
You get to shoot as much as you want.
Bad boys, bad boys
Hell, no.
Whatcha gonna do?
Whatcha gonna do when we come...?
Hey, hey, hey!
- No, no.
- No! No!
Never. Y'all will
never do that again.
Yeah, and you fucking up the lyrics,
which take a long time to learn.
- Don't do that.
- All right.
- No, no. Don't do that.
- Seriously.
- Okay.
- Sorry, sorry.
Shit.
- Won't happen again.
- Get your own damn song.
Can you believe that shit?
Dumbass.
Whatever, man.
Miss me with that bullshit.
I got this.
Hello there, ladies.
Georgio in there tonight?
- No idea who that is, sir.
- The line's in the back.
Nicole! Paige!
Hey!
- Hey!
- You guys look so good.
- Thank you.
- So beautiful. Oh, my God.
- You too.
That's my Uncle Michael,
and that's his pal, Uncle Marcus.
You mind if they come in?
He just got divorced.
- Oh, that is so sad.
- Yeah.
- Come on in. Come on in.
- Come on.
- Hell, no.
- Come on, kids. Let's go.
- Watch your step.
- Yeah.
- Oh, no.
- No, yeah.
- It's real.
- No, not at all.
- Yeah.
- No, sir.
Yeah.
Kelly, what's the target QTH?
Second level. VIP platform.
- I have eyes on.
- Up top.
Hi, baby.
Target confirmed.
Platform is one way in,
one way out.
We got him cornered.
Man on his two-side has a 55, hot.
Stay with the A-plan. Kelly,
you're on Zway Lo's bodyguard.
Copy.
Mike, how you think she DJ like that?
She must got some strong ass muscles.
Look, I'm gonna be honest
with you, Mike.
I ain't had sex in a long time.
Yeah, too long. Too long.
I be thinking of shit.
- Crazy shit, Mike.
- Marcus.
- I feel like I'm locked up since...
- Hey, you know they can hear you?
It's too loud. They can't hear us.
They can't hear us.
Look, look, sometime I go to
the Internet,
and I see some weird shit
on there.
- I saw a man put his...
- Marcus.
Marcus.
What?
We can hear you.
That's a little jokey joke.
Y'all didn't hear that, did you?
- In position.
- Setting up.
Mike, Marcus,
meet you at the top.
Mike and Marcus moving,
stairs right.
Rita on the move,
stairs left.
- Everybody in position?
- Set.
That dress is incredible, girl.
- You got style.
- Oh, hi.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Stand by. Stand by. Stand by.
I can't. I'm here
with my girlfriends.
They can come too, baby.
I can't tonight.
Knee him in his balls,
and let's go.
- From Tétouan.
- Bye, baby.
Why'd she wear that dress?
That is not a undercover dress.
You should've wore something...
undercover.
Happy birthday.
Yo, yo, yo! Everybody,
let's make some noise!
We got a special guest
in the house!
It's his birthday! Let's wish him
a birthday on one! Three, two, one.
Happy birthday!
We love you, Zway Lo!
Hey! Yeah!
- Zway Lo! Zway Lo!
- Top of the world, baby!
- Happy birthday, dickhead.
- Yeah!
- Yeah! Yeah!
- Yeah.
- You going to jail today, motherfucker.
When I say "criminal,
"you say "jail."
- Criminal.
- Jail.
Miami PD! Freeze.
- Damn!
I told you he was an athlete.
- We gotta jump.
- I'm not jumping.
- He's getting away! Jump now!
- Shit!
Zway Lo!
Get out of the way!
I need this. I need it.
Excuse me, sir.
- What you doing?
- Excuse me.
- Hey, hold on!
- Official police business.
- Hey, that's my car!
- This is the police.
Back up!
- What the fuck?
- Come on!
It is of no advantage for me to jump off
of the fucking thing if you're gonna take the stairs!
I told your ass I wasn't jumping!
Zway Lo just turned left
on 2nd Ave.
Shit!
- Putting your seat belt on?
- Yeah.
- That's how we do it now?
- You're damn right.
- Number one's on my ass!
- Crossing 395 into Overtown.
Whoa, Mike. Overtown's a no-go.
Zway got people here.
Dangerous people.
We're dangerous people.
Shit, whoa!
Damn Nerf gun,
rubber bullet bullshit.
They shooting slugs,
we firing gummy bears.
Mike, pull over for a minute.
I need to tell you something.
- Pull over?
- Yeah.
- One second. Let me see if Zway will pull over. Zway Lo!
- Yeah. Yeah.
Marcus needs to pull over for a second!
Hey, can we get a time-out?
- Damn it, Mike, I need to tell you something!
- What?
I made a promise to God.
- To who?
- To God.
What the hell are you talking about?
Look, I told the Lord that
if you made it through
that I would make no more violence.
He definitely knew you was bullshitting
with that. Violence is what we do.
It's about your soul, Mike.
Our job is to protect and serve.
You're damn right. I'm about
to serve this bitch right now.
- Oh, shit! What...?
- Oh, shit.
Oh, look at that!
Damn!
That is some Elephant Man shit right there.
Yo, you see that?
- Yeah, I see it.
- Hey, stop it.
- It's calling me, Mike.
- What?
- Leave it... Stop it.
- I can't help it, but it's calling me.
Stop. What the hell is wrong
with you? Just leave it alone.
Yo, leave it alone.
Leave... Marcus.
- You're gonna pop that shit, man.
- That shit nasty!
- Then leave it alone.
- Oh, shit.
Damn.
- Just leave it alone! Let's...
- No, one more time. One more again.
Overtown is waking up.
Let's go.
- AMMO, where you at?
- Got jammed up. Hitting Overtown now.
Gear up.
Come on.
Fuck!
We got your man!
- Shit!
- I'll kill his ass!
Oh, shit!
Stop it!
Wake up, Zway Lo!
Wake up! Wake up!
Wake your ass up!
Coach Burnett?
Dickhead.
Still think I'm a dickhead?
- Zway Lo, who wants to kill me?
- Shit, everybody wanna kill you.
Yeah, I told you, Mike.
Forget about me!
Kill them both!
What's he saying?
- Y'all both dying tonight.
- Coming up, Marcus.
Oh, shit.
Thank you, God!
Why'd you let him get away?!
Lay suppression fire!
- Oh, shit!
- Get in!
- There's a pit bull!
- Hey, come on!
Wanna get bit, you wanna get shot?
Come on! Let's go!
- Oh, shit.
- What you got?
It's like an angry
white man's basement in here.
- Shit, a fucking grenade.
- Pull it.
- Pull it!
- This ain't fucking Vietnam!
- Hang on to it, then.
- Damn you, Mike!
Oh, shit!
Come on, man!
What else you got?
Oh, yeah!
Shoot that shit!
No, no, Mike! I made a promise
to God! No more violence.
- Who do you think sent you that weapon?
- I don't know!
That is God's gun!
- It is?!
- Sent to you in your time of need.
- Well, shit! I do need it right now!
- Yes. You are a vessel for the Lord's work.
- Yeah, I'm a vessel.
- Like David and Goliath.
- Yeah, David with the slingshot.
- Yes! That is your slingshot!
- Yeah!
- To smite thine enemies!
- You know what? Bad boys of the Bible, baby!
- Exactly!
- Amen? Amen?
- Amen! Amen!
- Shit!
- Where are your glasses?
- I don't need no damn glasses!
- You ain't hitting shit!
Let's go!
Shit!
Get that ATV!
I got the six!
Yes!
No!
Mike! Mike! Mike!
What the hell you doing?!
Lord, I don't wanna die this way!
- Mike!
- Oh, shit!
- My bad, my bad.
- Damn right, that's your bad!
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
Mike! Mike!
Move!
Get out of the fucking way!
Hey, Dorn. I need you.
Hey, hey, look.
I been there before. Many times.
It's gonna be all right.
That's Zway Lo's phone.
Can you break it?
- Yeah. What am I looking for?
- Who he's talking to. Call logs.
And I need you to hurry up
just a little bit.
Okay, but I'm gonna have to go
on the dark side.
All right.
You good with that?
Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Let's do it.
Dorn, he's a big guy.
- How'd he get so good at this stuff?
- What stuff?
Tech shit.
- He looks like a killer.
- Is.
Used to be a bouncer.
Guy one night was getting
physical with a woman...
Yeah, big man lost it. Hit him.
- Bastard dropped dead.
- Avoided the fight ever since.
Here we go.
Give me the last two months.
Shit.
Mexico.
What are you after here?
All right. To each one of those numbers,
I need you to text the phrase:
Done.
All right. I got it.
Thank you.
- You sure?
- I got it. Go.
We're shut down.
- What?
- What do you mean?
AMMO's done.
I'm sorry.
Look, everything's gonna be all right.
Trust me on this, okay?
Everything's gonna be all right.
Mike.
You all right?
I think he's my son.
What?
Twenty-four years ago,
before we partnered up...
Captain Howard pulled me out
of the academy.
Nobody knew who I was.
He sent me in undercover
with the Aretas cartel.
Sorenson.
Weber.
Vargas. Carver.
All of the victims were on that case.
This is revenge.
- Yeah, Mike, but you weren't on that case.
- My name wasn't on it.
That's how deep I was.
I was Ricky Rollins.
Benito Aretas.
He's dead, Mike. He ain't after you.
Not him.
His wife.
Isabel.
I was her driver.
We connected so... deep.
We talked about everything.
She showed me the whole game.
How to walk it, how to talk it,
put clothes on it.
She made Mike Lowrey.
We fell in love.
- Are you telling me the one time that you...?
- Isabel Aretas.
The one time.
Takedown was coming.
DEA, ATF, everybody.
And I was gonna ghost
the whole operation.
Me and Isabel were gonna run away
with each other.
What made you change your mind?
They call her La Bruja.
The Witch.
She is into some dark shit.
Santa Muerte.
That woman...
was a stone-cold killer.
So I had to put the woman I love behind bars
for the rest of her life.
Chose the badge, and I've been
choosing it ever since.
Mike, you fucked a married witch?
So all the shit I just said,
and that was your takeaway?
No, it's just a lot to digest.
You think you know somebody and...
Hell, now it explains
why you dress like a drug dealer.
- So you wanna hear this shit or you don't?
- Sorry.
But you don't know that's your son, Mike.
You don't know who that witch was fucking.
Benito Aretas couldn't have kids.
Isabel gave birth in prison,
eight months after her arrest.
He said that to me before
I jumped from the chopper.
Me and Isabel made that up.
It's not even real Spanish.
It's some shit we said to each other.
It meant like,
"We'll be together until we burn."
The traitor is coming.
Get prepared.
We will.
Let's go!
- Nah, Mike.
- Marcus, he's the right age.
He's crazy like me. He's ruthless like me.
He's fearless like me.
He's the fucked-up me.
No, Mike.
You the fucked-up you.
You jumping to conclusions.
All right?
Shit's gonna work itself out.
You gotta trust that.
Yeah...
You're right.
Oh, man.
I love you, man.
- I gotta go. All right?
- Mike.
Mike.
Let me get past you there, sir.
Sorry there. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
That's the right spot
for me right there.
Excuse me, sir.
Seat right there.
Let me get by you. Watch your toes.
Watch your toes there.
It's all right.
There you go.
No, Marcus.
I'm not letting you go on
a suicide mission alone, Mike.
This is on me.
I'm not letting anybody else get killed
dealing with my shit.
Mike, she's a bruja.
She'll make your eyes melt
into your stupid-ass head.
She'll make your dick fall off.
I meant penis. You should be minding
your own business anyway.
Marcus, please go home.
We fly together. We die together.
- What?
- Oh, no.
That's just something we say.
It's all good. It ain't...
I can see how that got
y'all a little...
Where y'all from? Where you from?
So, what you gonna do when you see him?
You really gonna put your son behind bars?
No. I'm gonna kill him.
Kill him? You really gonna
kill your own son, Mike?
I'm gonna put him
in a fucking bag.
- You mind if we switch seats?
- Yeah, please.
Excuse me.
You realize you will
go to hell?
- I don't believe in hell, Marcus.
- Well, it believes in you.
I mean, killing your own son.
Brother, that's a darkness
that swallows you whole.
Well, maybe I already been swallowed.
I died, remember?
I'm ending this shit, man.
I should have known
he was your son.
Because the way
he whupped your ass, Mike.
That was a ass-whupping straight
from thy own loins.
A supernatural ass-whupping.
Can I be the godfather?
- You know what you can be, Marcus?
- What?
Quiet.
- Oh, I should be quiet?
- Yeah.
All right, you just had
a warlock baby with La Bruja,
who's trying to kill your ass,
probably mine too,
sucking our blood and all of that shit,
but I should be quiet.
Yeah.
Yeah, okay, Mike.
How you fuck a witch
without a condom?
You wrap that shit up, man.
- Hey, my man. We need to change seats.
- Yep. Okay.
Mike y Marcus.
This makes us even for Miami.
Yo, we hot.
- You called them again.
- Hey, Rita called me.
- What's up, fellas?
- Hey.
Hey. Hey.
I feel better when they're here.
Yeah, me too.
- Where'd you get all the toys?
- DEA station in Cuernavaca.
We capture her,
they take the credit.
Get ourselves killed,
they've got nothing to do with it.
All eyes on me.
I'm the bait. We meet at Hidalgo Palace.
It's an old hotel outside the city.
I'll keep her talking
till you guys spot the shooter.
- What if she just shoots you?
- Nah, she's gonna wanna talk.
We... have history.
Okay. Snatch and grab. We get them,
and we're on a plane to the States by dawn.
Dorn, get a floor-plan satellite image.
We'll have eyes on the outside and...
on the inside.
Hey. Nobody touches the shooter.
He's mine.
Yes, he is.
You coloring a little bit outside
the lines today, huh?
Don't die.
You make sure we both come home.
Still no identifiable threats.
Monitoring all channels inside.
Jamming everything outside, in case
they're running countersurveillance.
There's no way she's here alone.
It's the cartel.
She's gonna have serious backup.
Marcus is moving towards the back.
Marcus, we're covering
your position from the sky.
Still nothing.
Moving in closer.
Hola, Ricky.
Or should I call you Mike?
Hola, Isabel.
Not very thorough.
There was a time when touching me
would have melted you.
I'm gonna kill her myself.
Keep it.
Where is he?
This used to be our place.
I wanted you dead...
but you survived.
Perhaps I made you too strong.
Or perhaps...
Santa Muerte is
telling us something.
We were fated
to meet one more time.
This is some real telenovela shit.
I've taken care of that.
Shit.
I just lost all comms.
- Fuck. AMMO?
- Marcus, come in.
- Shit.
- They're jamming us.
- They know that we're here.
- This is fucked.
- I can't get back in.
- Still got Baby Barry on an outside frequency.
It's just us now.
Why didn't you tell me
I had a son?
What would you have done?
Taken care of him.
Like you took care of me?
It was gonna be a surprise.
After we ran away.
I'm seeing tactical movement. I've got
20 to 30 threats forming a perimeter.
We gotta go.
- Alt points of entry?
- Here.
That cold airflow could be
a laundry exhaust.
How could you do this to our son?
My son.
Who does he think I am?
Exactly who you are:
The coward, the traitor...
Don't do this.
Keep it moving, detective.
You see that?
Drop it.
Let's go!
What you gonna do?
No "el suego."
That means fire, right?
No, no "cate."
You and this man need to talk.
- It's some life-changing shit.
- Shut the fuck up.
- Easy on the barrel! Easy! No. Mike.
- Marcus, relax.
It's lack of communication
that got this shit fucked up.
He needs to tell you something. You ain't
gonna like it, but you need to hear it.
Oh, shit!
Yo, Mike, they're moving up
to the chopper!
Marcus!
- Put your glasses on!
- What the hell was that?
That was a bad throw!
Yo, Mike, careful!
- You were right about the glasses.
- I been telling your ass that shit for years.
Shit, this is like HD!
Go! Go! Go!
Contact! Twelve o'clock!
Go! Go, go, go!
Hey, Isabel and the shooter
went up the stairs.
Can you cover us?
- Kelly! Flank right!
- Copy!
- Rafe, pan left! Push!
- Copy that!
- Dorn, follow Rafe!
- Yup!
Hey, big man.
I'm gonna need you to hurt some people.
I'll pay for the therapy, all right?
I'm gonna need it. Seriously.
Yeah, I got you.
I'll hold the middle...
- and you push hard for the stairs.
- Push hard for the stairs.
Yeah.
Hey. It's good shit, lieutenant.
You too, detective.
You ain't such a dumbass after all.
On me!
Go!
Transition!
Shit.
- Shoot!
- Take them both!
Right there, right there!
Where the hell they getting
all these helicopters?
Mike!
- Take out the pilot!
- Take out the rotor!
- What are you aiming at?!
- The pilot!
Aim at the rotor!
If you shoot the pilot...
Got him!
Oh, shit!
Shit. You got a fucked-up family,
Mike.
The building's coming down!
We gotta move!
Mike! Marcus!
Shit.
On your knees, Isabel. Get down.
Mike!
Let that be a lesson
to your witch ass.
Armando...
you're my son.
You're my son.
I don't wanna fight.
Stay down.
I said, stay down.
I didn't know.
If I had known...
Mike, what are you doing?
I'm trying to penetrate his soul...
with my heart.
No.
No, Mike, no.
I was going through something.
Who are you?
I told you.
Liar.
Last chance.
Who are you?
Ask your mother.
Is it true what he says?
It doesn't matter.
He's nothing to you.
Hey, y'all see
all this fuego?
Can we take this shit outside?
Who is he?
- Tell him!
- Tell him, mama.
Is he my father?
Is he my father?!
Yes.
Kill him.
- No, no, wait, wait, wait...
- Shit.
Lay down. Down. Down.
Oh, shit.
Mike, we gotta go.
Mike! Gotta move! Now!
Mike! We gotta go!
Hold me! Hold me!
Oh, shit!
Mike! Don't let me go!
Don't let me go! Oh, shit!
Hold on. I got you.
Mike! I can't get to you!
I can't hold on.
Pull me up! Mike,
I don't wanna die this way!
Oh, Mike, I'm slipping.
Come on!
Hurry!
I can feel my ass cooking!
Come on.
Let's go! We gotta move!
Gunshot wound, upper chest!
We need medical!
- En route!
- All right.
- It's okay, I got him.
- Put him down.
- We need a trauma dressing.
- Right.
Relax.
I can't promise you
it's gonna be all good...
after all the stuff
you've done, but...
I can promise you
I'm gonna be there, all right?
Hey.
I'm your Uncle Marcus.
But we'll talk about that later.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
- Hey.
There we go.
- All right.
- Oh, my God.
You guys.
- There it is.
- Yes.
- Now it's time to raise your glasses...
- to our new captain.
- To our new captain.
- Hey, my mom says hey.
- You're not gonna let me live that down.
Oh, and, guys,
I got some news for you.
I just started therapy,
and my therapist thought it'd be super beneficial
if maybe we could hit up a group sesh together.
- It's super sick.
- Oh, for sure.
- Definitely.
- Yeah, we will be there.
- Marcus, let me holler at you for a second.
- Yeah.
Let me think about it.
- He want us to go to therapy.
- Yeah, I'm not going.
I'm not going.
Hey, man, look...
we don't say this kind of shit
to each other, man, but just...
thank you.
Mike, you don't have to thank me.
If you wanna retire,
just know that I am not
gonna try to stop you.
You earned it.
And I will support you 100,
no matter what.
But you're forgetting one thing.
We said for life.
For life, baby.
- There's my nephew.
- Yes.
- Hey.
- Little Marcus just woke up.
Okay, first things first.
Little surprise for you.
Three days at the Marion Springs Resort.
You know, kind of a little apology
for the spa day I crashed.
Yes, a little quality time, baby.
Quality time.
Yeah, baby, but Megan and
Reggie are on their honeymoon.
I got the baby this weekend.
Me and my AMMO squad.
You and Theresa go ahead, have fun.
You still got them blue pills, right?
I don't need no damn blue pills.
- That's what you said about your glasses.
- That baby looks good on you, Mike.
- You do look good holding a baby, Mike.
- Yeah, you think?
I do.
You good, Mike?
Let's go, team.
- Yep.
- Wait, nothing...
Wait, no. What you talking about?
Nah, we said we were doing this together.
Oh, no, I have to work. I'll check
on you tomorrow. I'll bring wine.
- Rita, stop playing. Hey, no.
- You'll need it.
- Y'all all agreed that we were all gonna stay with the baby.
- Marcus, I'm gonna see you. I'll be in the car.
- Just text my mom.
- Okay... Okay, that's not fun... No.
Okay. All right, all right.
Hey.
Bad boys, bad boys
Whatcha gonna do? Whatcha gonna do
when we come for you?
No. No, we not doing that
with the next generation.
- You gotta sing it right, man.
- All right.
- Bad boys, bad boys
- Whatcha gonna do?
- Whatcha gonna do when we come for you?
I'm gone.
How you doing?
I'm paying my debt.
It's a big one.
Opportunity may have presented itself
for you to pay down some of that debt.
You interested?
Yeah, man.
Would you fuck a witch
without a condom?
I would not.
He would not, Mike.